<?xml version='1.0' encoding='iso-8859-1'?>
<pod xmlns="http://axkit.org/ns/2000/pod2xml">
<head>
	<title>TIE Compiler Error Manual</title>
</head>
<sect1>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_ALREADY_DECL</title>
<para>
Duplicate variable declaration. For example, multiple declarations of
the same argument in a list (such as iclass operands) will generate
this error.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_ALREADY_DEFINED</title>
<para>
Duplicate definition of a TIE variable. All variables in the same scope
must have unique names. For example, two states cannot be defined with
the same name.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_ASSERT_FAILURE</title>
<para>
This error means that an assertion has failed in TC. We ask that you contact Tensilica support
and send us the resulting archive result.tgz which can be found in your TDK directory. This
will enable us to debug the problem, and hopefully resolve it in a timely manner.
</para>
<para>
Please try to rewrite the TIE that caused this internal error in TC. Most times a line number
and a filename of the TIE that caused the error was printed along with the error message.Try first
to rewrite this TIE.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="WARN_DEFAULT_OFF">TIE_ASSIGNMENT_WIDTH_MISMATCH</title>
<para>
The bit width of RHS and LHS in an assignment are not the same. This indicates that
there may be some truncation in the result, or in some cases undesirable zero extension
in the result.
This warning is not reported by default. To see it, you have to turn on the option
-warnall, or activate this specific warning with the flag -warn TIE_ASSIGNMENT_WIDTH_MISMATCH
</para>
<para>
Example of warning:
</para>
<verbatim><![CDATA[
wire [31:0] a, b;
wire [7:0] c = a | b;
]]></verbatim>
<para>
This will generate a warning that the RHS of the assignment is 32 bits and the LHS is 8 bits.
The correct way to write the code is
</para>
<verbatim><![CDATA[
wire [31:0] tmp = a|b;
wire [7:0] c = tmp[7:0];
]]></verbatim>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_BUFFER_OVERFLOW</title>
<para>
TIE compiler will not accept a single line of more than 6K characters. If a single
line that is longer than 6K characters is found, it generates this error.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_COMPMOD_ARG_ID</title>
<para>
When using TIEcomp, inputs of the TIEcomp module should be assigned
directly from variables in the current scope, and outputs of the TIEcomp 
module should be assigned directly to variables in the current scope. 
Any error is reported with this error code.
</para>
<para>
For example, when using the operation BAR as a TIEcomp, an error 
is generated as shown
</para>
<verbatim><![CDATA[
operation BAR { inout AR ars, in AR simm8 }
]]></verbatim>
<verbatim><![CDATA[
TIEcomp(BAR, { ars = a, simm8 = b }, { a = ars + 2, c = ars } );
]]></verbatim>
<para>
Error: (TIE_COMPMOD_ARG_ID),
        Each entry of the computation module's output argument
        list must specify an identifier on the right-hand
        side of the assignment. The identifier must specify
        an argument from the &quot;BAR&quot; operation.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_COMPMOD_ILLEGAL_ARG</title>
<para>
When using TIEcomp, assignments to and from variables that are not
inputs or outputs of the TIEcomp module are reported with this error.
For example, when using the operation BAR as a TIEcomp,
the following code will generate an error as shown
</para>
<verbatim><![CDATA[
operation BAR { inout AR ars, in AR simm8 }
]]></verbatim>
<verbatim><![CDATA[
TIEcomp(BAR, { ars = a, simm8 = b }, { a = ars, c = arr } );
]]></verbatim>
<para>
Error: (TIE_COMPMOD_ILLEGAL_ARG),
        The computation module's output argument list specifies
        an argument, &quot;arr&quot;, that is not an argument to the
        &quot;BAR&quot; operation.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_COMPMOD_ILLEGAL_INS</title>
<para>
Some Xtensa opcodes are not allowed to be used as TIEcomp, and when
used as TIEcomp generates this error. For example, the following code
will generate an error as shown
</para>
<para>
TIEcomp(CALLX, {ars = a}, {t = arr});
</para>
<para>
Error: (TIE_COMPMOD_ILLEGAL_INS),
        Instruction &quot;CALLX&quot; is not allowed in computation module.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_COMPMOD_MISSING_ARG</title>
<para>
When using TIEcomp, if any input of the TIEcomp module is not assigned,
or if an output of the TIEcomp module is not used, you will get this error.
For example, when using the operation BAR as a TIEcomp,
the following code will generate an error as shown
</para>
<verbatim><![CDATA[
operation BAR { inout AR ars, in AR simm8 }
]]></verbatim>
<verbatim><![CDATA[
TIEcomp(BAR, { ars = a }, { a = ars } );
]]></verbatim>
<para>
Error: (TIE_COMPMOD_MISSING_ARG),
        The computation module's input argument list is
        missing an assignment to argument &quot;simm8&quot; of operation &quot;BAR&quot;.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_COMPMOD_RECURSION</title>
<para>
The  TIEcomp invocation in an operation
directly or indirectly calls the same operation recursively.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_COMPMOD_INVOKE</title>
<para>
TIEcomp modules can be instantiated only in operation or reference. Instantiating
a TIEcomp module in a semantic or function will generate this error.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_CONFIG_COPROCESSOR_COUNT</title>
<para>
The tie description requires a coprocessor count
that is not specified in the Xtensa Config description. If you get this error,
you will have to rebuild your Xtensa configuration with the correct number
of coprocessors.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_CONFIG_PIF_WIDTH</title>
<para>
The memory width required by the tie description
cannot be accommodated by the Xtensa processor configuration selected. For example,
if you have a 128 bit register file, the load and store operations for the register
file will require a 128 bit memory interface in the base processor and if the
Xtensa config has a memory interface of 32 or 64 bits, you will get this error.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="WARN_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_CONSTANT_DECIMAL_OVERFLOW</title>
<para>
The integer constant value cannot be represented in 32 bits, causing overflow.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_CONSTANT_FORMAT</title>
<para>
An illegal format is used for a sized constant, e.g.
32'bff, since the binary format b can only have 0 and 1.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON|WARN_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_CONSTANT_ILLEGAL_SIZE</title>
<para>
The number of bits specified in a sized constant is illegal, e.g. 0'd3.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_CONSTANT_ILLEGAL_VALUE</title>
<para>
The value of a sized constant contains illegal characters, e.g 32'hYZ.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="WARN_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_CONSTANT_VALUE_OVERFLOW</title>
<para>
The constant number cannot be represented in the number of bits specified, eg. 4'd25.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="WARN_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_CONTEXT_SWITCH_EXPENSIVE</title>
<para>
In configurations supporting real time operation systems. It is recommended that 
all states and register files are put in a coprocessor in order to reduce the 
context switch overhead. This warning message is generated when the estimated
context switch overhead is too large.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_COPROC_MULTI_DEF</title>
<para>
Coprocessors with the same name are defined multiple times in the TIE file. 
However, they are not assgined to the same coprocessor number.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_COPROC_MAX_NUMBER</title>
<para>
The coprocessor number used  exceeds the maximum of 8 coprocessors allowed.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_COPROC_NUM_ILLEGAL</title>
<para>
The coprocessor number must be between 0 and 7. It is not necessary
to define a coprocessor with a number. If no number is assigned, the tie compiler
will automatically assign a number to the coprocessor.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_COPROC_NUM_USED</title>
<para>
The coprocessor number is already used by another coprocessor. It is not necessary
to define a coprocessor with a number. If no number is assigned, the tie compiler
will automatically assign a number to the coprocessor.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_COPROC_UNMAPPED_STATE</title>
<para>
The coprocessor includes a TIE state that is not mapped to programmer visible
user registers, which indicates that these states cannot be saved and restored
when Xtensa processor switches context to using a different coprocessor.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_CORE_INSTRUCTION</title>
<para>
Warning Level = 0 (Not suppressed by default)
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_CORE_NAME_DUP</title>
<para>
The variable is trying to redefine a previously declared variable in the
Xtensa core description. Note that this checking is done in a case sensitive way.
For example, the following tie will generate an error
</para>
<para>
field   S           slot0[19:16]
</para>
<para>
Error: (TIE_CORE_NAME_DUP),
        User tie type FIELD &quot;S&quot; is trying to redefine Xtensa
        core type FIELD &quot;s&quot; which is illegal. Names of the
        same type must be unique and cannot differ only in
        case.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_CSTUB_SWAP_CONCAT_INTF</title>
<para>
In cstub_swap construct, the concatenation must be a memory interface. That is,
it must be one of the following interfaces:
MemDataIn8, MemDataIn16, MemDataIn32, MemDataIn64, MemDataIn128, 
MemDataOut8, MemDataOut16, MemDataOut32, MemDataOut64, MemDataOut128
</para>
<para>
The interface must also be in the iclass of the corresponding instructions.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_CSTUB_SWAP_CONCAT_INTEGER</title>
<para>
In cstub_swap construct, the concatenation must span the entire interface.
It is not allowed to overlap any bit in the interface, nor is allowed
to neglect any bit.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="WARN_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_CTYPE_ALIGNMENT_LT_SIZE</title>
<para>
The alignment for the  ctype is less than the size of the ctype. Load/store
operations to read and write these ctypes from memory to register cannot be
automatically generated by the tie compiler.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_CTYPE_ALREADY_DEFINED</title>
<para>
The ctype is already defined. Note that a ctype can be automatically generated
by the tie compiler from a register file.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_CTYPE_FIELD_COUNT</title>
<para>
A structural ctype must contain more than one field.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_CTYPE_FIELD_CTYPE_CASE</title>
<para>
For a structural ctype that contains more than one register, the types of
each of its fields must be a valid ctype.  The TIE compiler did not find
a valid ctype, but did find a similar one.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_CTYPE_FIELD_DUP_NAME</title>
<para>
Two fields in a ctype must not have conflicting field names.  Two
field names conflict if they are the same under a case-insensitive
comparison.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_CTYPE_FIELD_INVALID_CTYPE</title>
<para>
For a structural ctype that contains more than one register, the types of
each of its fields must be a valid ctype.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_CTYPE_FIELD_INVALID_NAME</title>
<para>
The name of ctype fields must not contain a '.' or be a C/C++ keyword.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_CTYPE_FIELD_NESTED</title>
<para>
Structural ctypes must only contain ctypes that reference non-structural
ctypes.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="WARN_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_CTYPE_GENERATED_DEFAULT</title>
<para>
When a register file has two or more ctypes associated with it, one of them is 
selected to be the default ctype for that register file. You can explicitly 
select this by using the keyword default on the line that declares the ctype.
If a default ctype is not specified in the TIE description, the TIE compiler 
automatically chooses one as the default. It is recommended that you always 
explicitly specify the default ctype for register files with more than one 
ctype.
</para>
<para>
When a register file has more than one ctype associated with it, every 
instruction with one or more operands from the register file needs an 
instruction prototype. The instruction prototype specifies the ctype(s) 
associated with that instruction. If the instruction prototype is not 
specified in the TIE description, it is automatically generated by the 
TIE compiler using the default ctype as the ctype for every operand
of the register file.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_CTYPE_ILLEGAL_ALIGNMENT</title>
<para>
The alignment specification of a ctype must be a multiple of 8 bits (a byte),
not greater than 128 and must be a power of 2.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_CTYPE_ILLEGAL_DEFAULT</title>
<para>
The size of a default ctype must be greater than or equal to the regfile
entry size.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_CTYPE_ILLEGAL_DEFAULT_FIELD</title>
<para>
The default ctype for a register file must map to a single register or view.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_CTYPE_ILLEGAL_SIZE</title>
<para>
The size of the ctype must be less than or equal to the width of the register file
in which the ctype belongs. For example, the following tie will generate a warning
</para>
<para>
regfile XR 18 4 xr
ctype xrtype 24 32 XR
</para>
<para>
Warning: (TIE_CTYPE_ILLEGAL_SIZE),
        Ctype xrtype has size 24 which is greater then the
        size of the containing regfile. It is recommended
        that the ctype's size be made &lt;= to the regfile size.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_CTYPE_ILLEGAL_NAME</title>
<para>
Ctype names cannot have the character dot in them, since this will cause
illegal C code.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_CTYPE_NO_FIELD_PROTOS</title>
<para>
The TIE compiler does not automatically generate protos for ctypes with fields.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_CTYPE_NO_PREDEFINED</title>
<para>
Xtensa core register files such as AR cannot have user defined ctypes.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_CTYPE_NO_REGFILE</title>
<para>
The register file used by the ctype is not found in the tie description.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_CTYPE_REGFILE_CONFLICT</title>
<para>
The ctype name has a conflict with another register file name which the ctype
does not belong to. A ctype can have the same name as the register file which
it occupies.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="WARN_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_CTYPE_SIZE_GT_PIF</title>
<para>
The size of the ctype is greater than the memory access width of the Xtensa 
configuration selected. This means that reading or writing the ctype from
memory will involve multiple load or store instructions. Tie compiler cannot
automatically generate such instructions.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="WARN_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_CTYPE_SIZE_GT_STORE</title>
<para>
Store instructions cannot be automatically generated by tie compiler for
this ctype. This could be because the size of the ctype being greater than
memory access width of the Xtensa configuration selected, or the Xtensa
configuration not allowing stores of this size due to hardware restrictions.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="WARN_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_CTYPE_SIZE_LT_REGFILE</title>
<para>
The size of the ctype is smaller than the width of the register file it
occupies. This means that when reading or writing the ctype from
memory, the unoccupied bits will have to be set, either by zero extension
or sign extension, or any other algorithm. Load/Store instructions cannot 
be automatically generated by tie compiler for this ctype.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_DECODING_DUP_BIT</title>
<para>
The same bits in the instruction word is used more than once
for decoding a format or instruction. For example, the following tie description
will generate an error
</para>
<para>
format  xl64   64 { slot0, slot1 }  { InstBuf[2] == 1'b1 &amp;&amp; InstBuf[2:0]== 3'd7 }
</para>
<para>
Error: (TIE_DECODING_DUP_BIT),
        Bit InstBuf[2] is used multiple times in the decoding
        expression
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_DUP_VAR</title>
<para>
Duplicate variable name within a scope. For example, in the following code,
the operation TESTDUP reads a state called TESTDUP and generates an error
because in the body of the operation &quot;TESTDUP&quot; can be the state name or the
opcode name.
</para>
<para>
state TESTDUP  32 add_read_write
operation TESTDUP { out AR a } { in TESTDUP } { assign a = TESTDUP;}
</para>
<para>
Error: (TIE_DUP_VAR),
        In reference TESTDUP, the variable TESTDUP can be
        either STATE or OPCODE.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="WARN_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_EMPTY</title>
<para>
Empty tie description.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="WARN_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_ENCODING_FLIX_USED</title>
<para>
If the automatic instruction encoding uses bits in the instruction
word that are designated to FLIX length and format encoding, then
this warning is generated to make the user aware that the output
of this tie cannot be extended to add FLIX in future. The relevant
bits are the &quot;op0&quot; bits, which occupy InstBuf[3:0] and InstBuf[63:60] 
in a LittleEndian and BigEndian configuration respectively.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="WARN_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_ENCODING_FP_USED</title>
<para>
If the automatic instruction encoding uses bits in the instruction
word that are designated to the Floating point unit of Xtensa,
this warning is generated to make the user aware that the output
of this tie cannot be added to a Xtensa processor with the FPU.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="">TIE_ENCODING_MAC</title>
<para>
If the automatic instruction encoding uses bits in the instruction
word that are designated to the MAC16 unit of Xtensa,
this warning is generated to make the user aware that the output
of this tie cannot be added to a Xtensa processor with the MAC16 unit.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_ENCODING_RECURSIVE</title>
<para>
The encoding of an opcode references an opcode whose encoding reference
the first opcode, causing a recursive encoding.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="WARN_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_ENCODING_USED</title>
<para>
If the automatic instruction encoding uses bits in the instruction
word that are designated to a specific architectural option in the
Xtensa processor, this warning is generated to make the user aware 
that the output of this tie cannot be added to a Xtensa processor 
with that architectural option. For example, tie compiler may use
the Density instruction space Xtensa for encoding the operations
if the Xtensa configuration used does not have the Density instructions.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="WARN_DEFAULT_OFF">TIE_EXPRESSION_WIDTH_MISMATCH</title>
<para>
This warning is seen only when TIE compiler is run with the option -warnall.
It is suppressed by default.
</para>
<para>
According to TIE bit-width rules, which follow Verilog, a context-determined
expression is one where the bit-width of the expression depends on its
parent expression. In this case, the expression has a &quot;required-width&quot; that
is determined by the parent expression, as well as the &quot;computed-width&quot;. If
the required-width is different from the computed width, the expression and
its operands will be truncated or zero-extended as appropriate. If this is
undesirable, the user can run TIE compiler with the -warnall flag to see 
the mismatches.  The warning indicates that the computed width of an 
expression or the width of a variable in an expression is not the same 
as the required width of that expression or variable.  Please refer to
the Computation Section of the TIE Language Reference Manual for further
details of bit-width rules.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="WARN_DEFAULT_OFF">TIE_EXPRESSION_OPERAND_MISMATCH</title>
<para>
This warning is seen only when TIE compiler is run with the option -warnall.
It is suppressed by default.
</para>
<para>
According to TIE bit-width rules, which follow Verilog, if the operands of an 
operation have a &quot;required-width&quot;, then the operands are zero-extended or 
truncated as appropriate. If this is not desirable, then the user can run
the TIE compiler with the -warnall flag to see where the operands of an
operation are mismatched. Please refer to the Computation Section of the TIE 
Language Reference Manual for further details of bit-width rules.
</para>
<para>
This warning indicates that the two operands of an operation have different
bit width, and one of them will be zero extended. For example, the following
code will generate a warning as shown.
</para>
<para>
wire [3:0] a;
wire [4:0] b, c;
assign c = a + b;
</para>
<para>
Warning: (TIE_EXPRESSION_OPERAND_MISMATCH),
        Operands of arithmetic operation must have the same
        size, however the operand &quot;a&quot; is 4 bits and operand
        &quot;b&quot; is 5 bits
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_FEATURE_NOT_SUPPORTED</title>
<para>
If the Xtensa configuration or release of TIE compiler does not support the 
feature in the tie description, this error is generated.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_FIELD_CORE_DIFF_WIDTH</title>
<para>
A predefined field in Xtensa core is redefined with a different width. 
Xtensa core fields (such as &quot;s&quot;, &quot;r&quot;, &quot;t&quot;) can be redefined in user slots
in FLIX, but they have to be the same length.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_FIELD_DIFF_WIDTH</title>
<para>
A field can be defined more than once. In fact a field has to be defined
in every slot of a FLIX format where it is used for an opcode encoding.
However, the width of the field must be the same in all definitions. 
The following is illegal because the bit width of the field &quot;fldx&quot; is
7 bits in slot0 and 8 bits in slot1.
</para>
<para>
field fldx slot0[10:4] 
field fldx slot1[7:0]
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_FIELD_INDEX_ORDER</title>
<para>
Incorrect indexing of a field. The  only indexing allowed is
field[ from:to ], where from is &gt;= to.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_FIELD_INDEX_RANGE</title>
<para>
Incorrect indexing of a field[from:to], either one of the indices
is beyond the width of the field.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_FIELD_MULTI_DEF</title>
<para>
A field can be defined more than once. In fact a field has to be defined
in every slot of a FLIX format where it is used for an opcode encoding.
However, it cannot be defined more than once in the same slot.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_FIELD_NO_SLOT</title>
<para>
Field is not defined in any slot.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_FIELD_OVERLAP_BITS</title>
<para>
Definition of a field uses specific bits of a slot more than once.
For example, in the following code, the field definition of &quot;rts&quot;
uses the bit s[2] more than once.
</para>
<para>
field   rts  {r,s[2:0], t, s[3:2]}
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_FIELD_SLOT_CONFLICT</title>
<para>
Field names and slot names must be unique in a case-sensitive way.
This is to avoid duplicate variable names generated by TIE compiler
in software libraries. For example, a field name &quot;SLOTa&quot; and a slot
name &quot;slota&quot; will be illegal.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_FIELD_TOO_LARGE</title>
<para>
The field width is bigger than the slot it occupies.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_FILE_READ_FAIL</title>
<para>
TIE compiler could not read the tie file.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_FILE_WRITE_FAIL</title>
<para>
TIE compiler could not write a file to generate the tdk.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_FORMAT_ALREADY_DEFINED</title>
<para>
A format with the same name as already been defined.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_FORMAT_COUNT</title>
<para>
The maximum number of formats allowed is 7.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_FORMAT_FORMAT_OVERLAP</title>
<para>
The decoding logic of two formats overlap. For example, in the
following code (assuming a 64 bit instruction word in a little
Endian configuration), the decoding logic for &quot;xl64&quot; and &quot;m64&quot;
are overlapping because they are both the default decoding
logic for length len64.
</para>
<para>
length  len64      64    { InstBuf[3:0] == 15 }
</para>
<para>
format  x64        len64   { slot0, slot1 }   
format  m64        len64   { slot2 }
</para>
<para>
slot    slot0       x64 [29:4]     
slot    slot1       x64 [63:30]   
slot    slot2       m64 [27:4]
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_FORMAT_INSTR_CONNECT_LIMIT</title>
<para>
The total number of connected groups of operations in a format exceeds the limit 15. 
A group of operations is all operations that share the same slots in the format. For example:
</para>
<para>
operation FOO and BAR are in the same group, because they are only defined in slot0. 
operation TEE is not in the same group as operation FOO and BAR, because it is also defined in slot3.
</para>
<para>
Two groups of operations are considered connected if they have at least one slot in common. In
the above example, operations FOO and BAR are connected to operation TEE, because they are all defined in slot0. 
However, operation KII is not connected to either operations FOO/BAR and operation TEE, because they do not
have one slot in common.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_FORMAT_LENGTH_DISJOINT</title>
<para>
A format and the length of the format have conflicting decoding logic. For
example, in the following code, the format &quot;x64&quot; defines a decoding logic
of &quot;InstBuf[3] == 1'b0&quot;, but the length &quot;len64&quot; which it uses has the
decoding logic of &quot;InstBuf[3:0] == 4'b1111&quot; which means InstBuf[3] has a conflict.
</para>
<para>
length  len64      64      {InstBuf[3:0] == 4'b1111}
format  x64        len64   { slot0, slot1 }    {InstBuf[3] == 1'b0&quot;}
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_FORMAT_SLOT_DISJOINT</title>
<para>
The bits used by the decoding logic of a format are also being used by a slot
in the format. For example, in the following code, InstBuf[4] is being used
for decoding the format x64. The slot &quot;slot1&quot; as defined here also occupies bit
InstBuf[4].
</para>
<para>
length  len64      64    {InstBuf[3:0] == 4'b1110 }
format  x64        len64 {slot1} {InstBuf[4] == 1'b1 }
slot slot1 x64[55:0]
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_FORMAT_OVERLAP_SLOTS</title>
<para>
Slots in a format overlap. For example, in the following code, both
the slots &quot;slot0&quot; and &quot;slot1&quot; occupy InstBuf[29].
</para>
<para>
length  len64      64      {InstBuf[3:0] == 4'b1111}
</para>
<para>
format  x64        len64   { slot0, slot1 }
</para>
<para>
slot    slot0      x64 [29:4] 
slot    slot1      x64 [63:29]
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_FORMAT_SLOT_COUNT</title>
<para>
TC restricts the number of slots in one format to 8.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_FORMAT_MAX_SLOT_COUNT</title>
<para>
XCC compiler restricts the total number of slots to 64.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_FORMAT_SLOT_NOT_DEFINED</title>
<para>
Slot referred in the format statement has not been defined.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_FORMAT_SLOT_NOT_SPECIFIED</title>
<para>
All slots in a format must be specified in the format definition to specify the
ordering of slots in the assembly code.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_FORMAT_SLOT_OPCODE_ENCODING</title>
<para>
The encoding of an opcode in a slot uses a field that overlaps with 
the decoding bits for the format to which the slot belongs to. This
is legal as long as the encoding specified assigns the overlapping
bits to the same value, in which case the same bits will be used
for decoding the format as well as an opcode in the format. However,
it is illegal to assign the bits to different values, or to use
the bits used for decoding for an operand.
</para>
<para>
For example, in the following code, the slot &quot;slot0&quot; occupies &quot;InstBuf[31:0]&quot;, 
and field &quot;op0A&quot; which is defined as &quot;slot0[7:4]&quot; occupies &quot;InstBuf[7:4]&quot;. 
The encoding of opcode &quot;MYOP&quot; assigns bits &quot;InstBuf[7:4] = 4'b0000&quot;, 
which conflicts with the decoding of the format, which assigns 
&quot;InstBuf[4] = 1'b1&quot;. Note that encoding of &quot;MYOP&quot; as &quot;op0A=4'0001&quot; 
would be legal.
</para>
<para>
length  len64      64      		    {InstBuf[3:0] == 4'b1111}
</para>
<para>
format  x64        len64   { slot0, slot1 } { InstBuf[4] == 1'b1 }
</para>
<para>
slot    slot0      x64[31:0]
slot    slot1      x64[63:32]
</para>
<para>
field   op0A 	   slot0[7:4]
opcode  MYOP	   op0A=4'b0000
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_FORMAT_SLOT_ILLEGAL</title>
<para>
A FLIX format cannot use Xtensa core slot &quot;Inst&quot; directly. User is
required to create his/her own slots and add Xtensa Core opcodes
that are allowed to be in FLIX to the slots.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_FORMAT_WRONG_DECODER</title>
<para>
Legal decoding expressions for decoding formats are restricted to the form
</para>
<para>
InstBuf[from:to] == &lt;constant&gt; [ &amp;&amp; InstBuf[from:to] == &lt;constant&gt; ]
</para>
<para>
This is to ensure that the decoding logic can meet the timing constraints
for decoding the instruction. Decoding logic should not have arbitrary 
amount of logic.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_FORMAT_NO_DECODER</title>
<para>
If there are multiple formats in FLIX, each format needs to have a decoding
expression using some of the bits in the instruction word. TIE compiler can 
generate the encoding automatically if there are bits available. However, if the
slots in a format leave no bits for encoding a format, it is an error.
For example, in the following code, there are no bits to encode format
&quot;x64&quot;, because the slots &quot;slot0&quot; and &quot;slot1&quot; occupy all the bits.
</para>
<para>
length  len64      64      {InstBuf[3:0] == 4'b1111}
format  x64        len64   { slot0, slot1 } 
format  y64        len64   { slot0, slot2, slot3 }
</para>
<para>
slot    slot0      x64 [31:4] 
slot    slot1      x64 [63:32]
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_FORMAT_NO_LENGTH</title>
<para>
Each length has to be decoded in FLIX. The only bits allowed to be
used for decoding length are InstBuf[3:0] in LittleEndian or
InstBuf[63:60] in BigEndian Xtensa configurations respectively.
Furthermore, the only encoding space available for length
are the values &quot;4'd14&quot; and &quot;4'd15&quot; for these bits. Therefore,
a maximum of two length specifications can be encoded. Also,
these encoding values should not conflict with opcode encodings
if the same bits are used for a slot.
</para>
<para>
If TIE compiler is unable to generate a decoding for the length
specified in the format within these bits due to lack of encoding
space, then this error is generated.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_FORMAT_LENGTH_OVERLAP</title>
<para>
Each length has to be decoded in FLIX. The only bits allowed to be
used for decoding length are InstBuf[3:0] in LittleEndian or
InstBuf[63:60] in BigEndian Xtensa configurations respectively.
Furthermore, the only encoding space available for length
are the values &quot;4'd14&quot; and &quot;4'd15&quot; for these bits. Therefore,
a maximum of two length specifications can be encoded. Also,
these encoding values should not conflict with opcode encodings
if the same bits are used for a slot.
</para>
<para>
If TIE compiler is unable to generate a decoding for the length
specified in the format within these bits due to slots in the format
overlapping these bits, then this error is generated.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_FUNCTION_ALREADY_DECLARED</title>
<para>
A function with the same name has been already declared.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_FUNCTION_INPUT_ARG</title>
<para>
Number of arguments in a TIE function call does not match the number
of function inputs.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_FUNCTION_INTERNAL_NAME</title>
<para>
A TIE function cannot have the same name as a TIE module.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_FUNCTION_IO_NAME</title>
<para>
Duplicate input/output name found in a function declaration. All inputs and
outputs must be unique. The function name is also the output name.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_FUNCTION_RECURSIVE</title>
<para>
A TIE function recursively calls the same function, either directly
or by instantiating another function.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_FUNCTION_SHARED</title>
<para>
A TIE function cannot instantiate a shared function. Shared functions
can only be called from an instruction.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="WARN_DEFAULT_OFF">TIE_FUNCTION_UNUSED</title>
<para>
A TIE function is defined but not used. No hardware is generated for this.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_FUNCTION_IO_DECL</title>
<para>
Illegal function input/output declaration. 
Legal syntax for function declaration is
</para>
<para>
function bit-range function-name ( bit-range input-name [, bit-range input-name])
where bit-range must be specified as [from:to] where from &gt; to. 
For 1 bit inputs/outputs, [0:0] should be omitted.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="WARN_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_FUTURE_VERSION</title>
<para>
The variable name is a keyword in a future version of TIE language. It is
preferable to use a different name so that when upgrading to the next
version of TIE language, the tie description will work without modification.
For example, the name &quot;queue&quot; is a keyword in LX version and should be
avoided as a variable name even if not using LX at this time.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="">TIE_GENERATE</title>
<para>
TIE compiler automatically generates opcode encodings and operands from
operation and register file descriptions. Any error in this process is
reported as TIE_GENERATE with a unique message that explains the problem
encountered. Common errors are:
</para>
<list>
<item><itemtext>no encoding space found for encoding the opcodes</itemtext>
</item>
<item><itemtext>operations to load/store register file could not be generated</itemtext>
</item>
<item><itemtext>operation arguments could not be coalesced to operands as 
   specified due to constraints such as a combined semantic.</itemtext>
</item>
</list>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="MSG_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_GENERATED_OPERATION</title>
<para>
TIE compiler will report all the operations it automatically generated.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_ICLASS_ARG_MULTIPLE_DECL</title>
<para>
Same argument is declared more than once in an iclass.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_ICLASS_COND_KILL</title>
<para>
If an instruction has a conditional kill on an output operand/state,
all instructions that share the iclass must also have conditional kill.
This is to avoid the compiler incorrectly inferring the instruction 
without the conditional kill as read-modify-write.
</para>
<para>
For example, the following is illegal. You have to put MYMOVE and
MYCONDMOVE in different iclasses.
</para>
<para>
opcode MYMOVE     op2=5 CUST0
opcode MYCONDMOVE op2=6 CUST0
iclass test_kill { MYMOVE, MYCONDMOVE } { out arr, in ars } 
reference MYMOVE     { assign arr = ars; }
reference MYCONDMOVE { assign arr = ars; assign arr_kill = ~(ars[0]); }
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_ICLASS_CORE_ICLASS</title>
<para>
The iclass name conflicts with a predefined iclass in the Xtensa core.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_ICLASS_CORE_OPERAND</title>
<para>
The operand is an Xtensa core operand that cannot be used by user TIE.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_ICLASS_CORE_STATE</title>
<para>
The state is an Xtensa core state that cannot be used by user TIE.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="WARN_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_ICLASS_DIFF_SLOT</title>
<para>
For an opcode to belong to a slot, all fields required for encoding
the opcode and operands must be declared in the slot.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_ICLASS_DUPLICATE_OPCODE</title>
<para>
Opcode name is declared more than once in a iclass.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_ICLASS_IMM_OPERAND_DIR</title>
<para>
Immediate ranges/operands, fields and tables can only be declared as inputs.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_ICLASS_INTERFACE_DIR</title>
<para>
The direction of the interface in the iclass/operation does not match the
direction in the definition of the interface. For example, the memory
address interface &quot;VAddr&quot; can only be declared as an &quot;out&quot;.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_ICLASS_LOADBYTEDISABLE</title>
<para>
The interface LoadByteDisable is used for arbitrary byte enables for loads
and can be used only for load operations (using MemDatIn).
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_ICLASS_MEMDATA</title>
<para>
An operation can only do a load (using MemDataIn*) or a store (using MemDataOut*)
The same operation cannot do a load and a store. This is illegal in the current
Xtensa architecture.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_ICLASS_MEMDATAIN</title>
<para>
An operation can use only one size of load data (MemDataIn). Legal values
of MemDataIn are 8,16,32,64 and 128. The legal values also depend on the
data memory width of the Xtensa processor core.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_ICLASS_MEMDATAOUT</title>
<para>
An operation can use only one size of store data (MemDataOut). Legal values
of MemDataOutIn are 8,16,32,64 and 128. The legal values also depend on the
data memory width of the Xtensa processor core.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_ICLASS_NO_MEMDATA</title>
<para>
Load/Store operations must use the interfaces VAddr and MemDataIn/Out
interfaces together. These interfaces cannot be used independently.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_ICLASS_NO_VADDR</title>
<para>
Load/Store operations must use the interfaces VAddr and MemDataIn/Out
interfaces together. These interfaces cannot be used independently.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_ICLASS_OPERAND_NUM</title>
<para>
XCC compiler restricts the number of operands in an operation to 512.
Operands include all input/output arguments, states and interfaces
(including tie ports).
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_ICLASS_OPERAND_REGFILE_NUM</title>
<para>
The total number of inputs/output read and written from an instruction
to a register file must not exceed the number of entries in the register
file. For example, if a register file has 4 entries, an operation cannot
declare more than 4 operands (inputs + output) from the register file,
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_ICLASS_STOREBYTEDISABLE</title>
<para>
The interface StoreByteDisable is used for arbitrary byte enables for stores
and can be used only for store operations (using MemDataOut).
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="WARN_DEFAULT_OFF">TIE_ILLEGAL_CONST</title>
<para>
If a constant definition has &quot;X&quot; in it, these will be converted to &quot;0&quot;.
This warning is suppressed by default. Run TIE compiler with flag
-warnall to see it.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_ILLEGAL_COPROC</title>
<para>
Coprocessor includes undefined states or register files.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_ILLEGAL_ID</title>
<para>
Valid names in TIE language must contain valid alphanumeric characters.
Names cannot start or end with &quot;_&quot; or &quot;.&quot;. Names cannot also start with
&quot;TIE_&quot;.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_ILLEGAL_IMM_OPERAND</title>
<para>
Illegal immediate operand description. Immediate operands must have the description
</para>
<para>
operand name field_name decoding_expression encoding_expression
</para>
<para>
decoding expression must only use the operand name and table name
encoding expression must only use the field name and table name
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_ILLEGAL_INTEGER</title>
<para>
The integer value specified is incorrect. For example, in an immediate range
specification, the integer value for the step size must be a power-of-2, and the
lower and upper values must be a multiple of the step size. 
Following are some examples of illegal code
</para>
<para>
immediate_range ir1 0 255 3 
immediate_range ir3 0 255 2
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_ILLEGAL_LHS_ASSIGNMENT</title>
<para>
The left hand side of an assignment can only be a variable name or a
concatenation of two variables.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_ILLEGAL_RANGE</title>
<para>
Immediate range low value must be less than high value
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="">TIE_ILLGAL_RANGE_VALUE</title>
<para>
Immediate range low and high value must be valid integers
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="WARN_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_ILLEGAL_REG_OPERAND</title>
<para>
Error in specifying register operands. The valid syntax is
operand name field-name {register-file[field-name]}
The common problems are:
</para>
<list>
<item><itemtext>using 0 or more than one register file name in decoding</itemtext>
</item>
<item><itemtext>using 0 or more than one field name in decoding</itemtext>
</item>
<item><itemtext>field used in decoding is not the same as the field used in declaration</itemtext>
</item>
<item><itemtext>field used to index the register file has more bits than needed (warning)</itemtext>
</item>
<item><itemtext>using an encoding expression, which is illegal for register operand</itemtext>
</item>
<item><itemtext>using an illegal variable name in decoding</itemtext>
</item>
</list>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_ILLEGAL_REPLICATION</title>
<para>
Replication must have an integer amount that is &gt; 0.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_ILLEGAL_SYNTAX</title>
<para>
Syntax Error.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_ILLEGAL_COMPMOD</title>
<para>
A TIEcomp module must be a valid operation or an instruction with a reference.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_IMAP_ARG_DIR</title>
<para>
The direction of the first appearance of an IMAP argument must match the direction
that is declared in the argument list. If the argument is declared as direction in,
the first appearance of the argument needs to be an in or inout operand of an 
instruction. If the argument is declared as out, its first appearance needs to be
an out operand of an instruction. If the argument is declared as inout, its
first appearance needs to be an in or inout operand of an instruction. Please note
the first appearance of a temporary needs to be of an out operand type.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_IMAP_ARG_DUP</title>
<para>
The same name appear multiple times in IMAP argument or temporary list.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_IMAP_ARG_NO_POINTER</title>
<para>
No pointer type is allowed in IMAP argument list, please use AR type instead.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_IMAP_ARG_UNKNOWN</title>
<para>
An argument or temporary has an unknown type.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_IMAP_CODEARG_NUM</title>
<para>
The number of argument listed in IMAP code is different from the number
of argument of the iclass of the corresponding instruction.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_IMAP_CODEARG_REGFILE</title>
<para>
IMAP code argument accesses a different register file from the one
specified in the corresponding iclass.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_IMAP_CODEARG_TYPE</title>
<para>
IMAP code argument has a different type from the one specified in
the corresponding iclass.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_IMAP_CODEARG_UNKNOWN</title>
<para>
An implementation or pattern code argument cannot be found in the
argument or temporary list.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_IMAP_COPY_DEST_TYPE</title>
<para>
The destination of a pseudo-copy instruction needs to be of register type.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_IMAP_CYCLIC_MAP</title>
<para>
If the input pattern of the imap only contains one instruction, the number of
operands of the instruction in the input pattern must be greater than the 
number of operands in the instruction in the output pattern. The method to
calculate the number of operands is as follows: input and output operands are
counted as one; inout operands are counted as two.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="">TIE_IMAP_IMMD</title>
<para>
Immediate operands can only be used once in the implementation/pattern.
It is a restriction of the current release.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_IMAP_INVALID_OPCODE</title>
<para>
The opcode is not a defined Xtensa ISA instruction, nor a user TIE instruction.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_IMAP_NO_CODE</title>
<para>
The body of implementation or pattern needs to have at least one non-pseudo-copy
instruction.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_IMAP_MULTI_ASSIGN</title>
<para>
One argument or temporary is assigned multiple times in a single instruction.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_IMAP_MULTI_INSTR</title>
<para>
Only one instruction can appear in implementation.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_IMM_OPERAND_DECODE</title>
<para>
Decoding expression of immediate operands cannot be more than 32 bits.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_IMM_OPERAND_NO_ENCODING</title>
<para>
Missing encoding expression for immediate operand.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_INCORRECT_NUMBER_OF_ARGUMENTS</title>
<para>
The number of arguments expected by the construct was not matched.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_INSTR_GROUP_ALL</title>
<para>
If an instruction group (such as &quot;xt_logical&quot;) is used in slot_opcodes, 
no instruction from that group can be added individually. Some groups
such as xt_widebranch* can only be used as a group.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_INSTR_GROUP_MULTIPLE</title>
<para>
Only one instruction group of this class can be instantiated. This is
applicable to wide branch instructions. Only one class of wide
branch instructions can be added in FLIX. For example, adding
xt_widebranch18 and xt_widebranch16 is illegal.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_INST_NO_SLOT</title>
<para>
Instruction does not appear in any slot. If the user TIE has no
FLIX format, the tie instruction goes into the default 24 bit
&quot;Inst&quot; slot. If the user TIE has FLIX, user should put the
opcodes in slot(s) by adding a slot_opcode statement. If an
opcode is not in any slot_opcode statement, then it is put into
the Inst slot by default.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_INST_MISSING_XFLIX_PROPERTY</title>
<para>
Every core instruction should have either enFLIX property or
nonFLIX property set. User instruction, however, may not have
such properties.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_INST_NAME_RESERVED</title>
<para>
Instruction names starting with &quot;ld.&quot;, &quot;st.&quot;, or &quot;mv.&quot; and 
finishing with a regfile or ctype name are reserved by TC. 
Instructions with those names must appear in at one of the
&quot;loadi&quot;, &quot;storei&quot;, and &quot;move&quot; protos. The instructions must
be the only instruction in those protos.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_INTERFACE_CONN</title>
<para>
Predefined interfaces such as &quot;VAddr&quot; or &quot;MemDataIn/Out&quot; should not
be declared by the user. These are automatically declared. If the
user does declare them, the interface specification must be the
predefined specification.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_INTERFACE_DIR</title>
<para>
Predefined interfaces such as &quot;VAddr&quot; or &quot;MemDataIn/Out&quot; should not
be declared by the user. These are automatically declared. If the
user does declare them, the interface specification must be the
predefined specification.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_INTERFACE_ILLEGAL</title>
<para>
Illegal interface description. Note that
Predefined interfaces such as &quot;VAddr&quot; or &quot;MemDataIn/Out&quot; should not
be declared by the user. These are automatically declared. If the
user does declare them, the interface specification must be the
predefined specification.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_INTERFACE_ILLEGAL_DEFAULT</title>
<para>
Internal use only. Please report to Tensilica.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_INTERFACE_ILLEGAL_DEPENDENCY</title>
<para>
Internal use only. Please report to Tensilica.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_INTERFACE_INTERNAL</title>
<para>
Using an unsupported interface.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_INTERFACE_KILL_USE</title>
<para>
The KILL signal for a TIE queue can only be assigned from an operation
if the operation reads or writes the queue. If the operation argument
list does not include the queue name, then it is illegal to add the
Q_KILL interface of the queue to the operation.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="WARN_DEFAULT_OFF">TIE_INTERFACE_LSSIZE_IGNORED</title>
<para>
LSSize is an obsolete interface in the TIE language that was used to
describe the size of the load/store memory data. This is no longer
used. TIE compiler automatically derives the size. An old version
of tie run with a new version of TIE compiler wil generate this 
warning. Please remove LSSize from your tie description.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_INTERFACE_MAX_WIDTH</title>
<para>
Maximum width of a tie port interface is 1024 bits.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_INTERFACE_NAME_CONFLICT</title>
<para>
The tie port interface will generate either a top level port 
signal whose name will conflict with an another port. For example,
the following tie will generate a top level input port called &quot;TIE_IQ_Empty&quot;
from the queue &quot;IQ&quot;, and another top level port called &quot;TIE_IQ_Empty&quot;
from the import wire &quot;IQ_Empty&quot;.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_INTERFACE_READ_STAGE</title>
<para>
Illegal read/use stage for a tieport interface. This is an internal error
and if reported indicates that the TIE compiler did not elaborate
a tie port correctly to its internal format. It should be reported
to Tensilica.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_INTERFACE_STALL_ILLEGAL</title>
<para>
Illegal stall specification for a tie port interface.  This is an internal error
and if reported indicates that the TIE compiler did not elaborate
a tie port correctly to its internal format. It should be reported
to Tensilica.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="WARN_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_INTERFACE_STALL_USE</title>
<para>
The tie port interface is internally used for generating a stall and should
not be directly used in a operation. For example, the Empty/Full interface of 
a queue, if read directly into an operation will generate this warning,
because it is used to generate a stall automatically. The signal NOTRDY 
should be used to check the status of the queue.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_INTERFACE_TYPE</title>
<para>
Illegal type in interface description. Note that
Predefined interfaces such as &quot;VAddr&quot; or &quot;MemDataIn/Out&quot; should not
be declared by the user. These are automatically declared. If the
user does declare them, the interface specification must be the
predefined specification.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_INTERFACE_WIDTH</title>
<para>
Illegal width in interface description. Note that
Predefined interfaces such as &quot;VAddr&quot; or &quot;MemDataIn/Out&quot; should not
be declared by the user. These are automatically declared. If the
user does declare them, the interface specification must be the
predefined specification.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_INTERFACE_WRITE_STAGE</title>
<para>
Illegal write/def stage for a tieport interface. This is an internal error
and if reported indicates that the TIE compiler did not elaborate
a tie port correctly to its internal format. It should be reported
to Tensilica.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_INTERNAL</title>
<para>
Internal error in TIE compiler due to a bug. When this happens, the file
tc_errlog.txt in the tdk directory may have more information.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_KEYWORD</title>
<para>
A TIE/C/Verilog language keyword cannot be used as the name of a tie variable.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_LENGTH_ALREADY_DEFINED</title>
<para>
A lwngth with the same name as already been defined.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_LENGTH_OVERLAP</title>
<para>
The decoding logic of two lengths overlap. For example, in the
following code (assuming a 64 bit instruction word in a little
Endian configuration), the decoding logic for &quot;len64&quot; and &quot;len32&quot;
are overlapping.
</para>
<para>
length  len64     64    { InstBuf[3:0] == 15 }
length  len32     32    { InstBuf[3:0] == 15 }
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_LENGTH_WRONG_DECODER</title>
<para>
Legal decoding expressions for decoding length are restricted to the form
</para>
<para>
InstBuf[from:to] == &lt;constant&gt; [ &amp;&amp; InstBuf[from:to] == &lt;constant&gt; ]
</para>
<para>
This is to ensure that the decoding logic can meet the timing constraints
for decoding the instruction. Decoding logic should not have arbitrary 
amount of logic. Also, the length decoding can only use bits InstBuf[3:0]
or InstBuf[63:60] in LittleEndian and BigEndian configurations respectively.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_LENGTH_WRONG_SIZE</title>
<para>
Incorrect length size. Legal lengths are 32 or 64 as the configuration permits.
For example, a configuration with a instruction word length of 32 cannot have
a length declaration of size 64.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_LENGTH_SLOT_DISJOINT</title>
<para>
The bits used by the decoding logic of a length are also being used by a slot
in the format. For example, in the following code, InstBuf[3:0] is being used
for decoding the format x64. The slot &quot;slot1&quot; as defined here occupies bits
InstBuf[60:0]. Therefore the bits InstBuf[3:0] has a conflict.
</para>
<para>
length  len64      64    {InstBuf[3:0] == 4'b1110 }
format  x64        len64 {slot1} 
slot slot1 x64[60:0]
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_LICENSE</title>
<para>
Could not get a license for a specific feature. The TIE compiler needs a license
to run, and specific licenses for H/W generation and are LX are also needed.
TIE compiler uses FLEXLM license mechanism. Please check license availability
using &quot;lmstat&quot; command.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_LIST_OVERLAP</title>
<para>
Some TIE variables can appear in only one list. The same opcode cannot appear
in the instruction list of more than one iclass, schedule, or semantic.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="WARN_DEFAULT_OFF">TIE_LOADSTORE_NO_PROTO</title>
<para>
If a load or store instruction is explicitly written by the user, then
a proto should also be written for the instruction with the appropriate
argument for data and address. Otherwise, the TIE compiler will generate
a proto for the load and store which may be incorrect.
</para>
<para>
If the TIE compiler generates the load or store instruction, then the
proto will also be generated correctly.
</para>
<para>
This warning is not seen by default, unless the TIE compiler is run with
the flag -warnall.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_LOOKUP_WRITE_STAGE</title>
<para>
A lookup request can be written in the stages E to W only.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_LOOKUP_LATENCY</title>
<para>
The latency of the lookup operation is (read stage - write stage) of the
lookup. Since the latency must be &gt;= 1, therefore the read stage of the 
lookup must be at least one cycle after the write stage.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_LOOKUP_RDY</title>
<para>
A &quot;Rdy&quot; input in a lookup is used to indicate if the external device
is accepting the lookup request sent by Xtensa processor. If &quot;Rdy&quot; is
low, the processor stalls. To make this stall be interruptible by 
external interrupts or internal exceptions, the stall must be effective
before the instruction commit stage (W). Therefore, Rdy is allowed only
</para>
<list>
<item><itemtext>in stage E in a 5-stage configuration</itemtext>
</item>
<item><itemtext>in stage L in a 7-stage configuration.</itemtext>
</item>
</list>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_LOOKUP_USAGE</title>
<para>
Lookup consists of an output and an input port that must be used atomically within
an instruction. This means that an operation or instruction must use both interface
or port. It is illegal to use the interfaces individually.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_LOOKUP_INVALID_WIDTH</title>
<para>
Lookup input and output width must be a positive number.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_LS_UNIT_ALLOCATION_ERROR</title>
<para>
Xtensa processor supports upto 2 load/store units for FLIX configurations. With
two load/store units, a FLIX format can have load/store instructions in two slots.
However, with one load/store unit, load/store instructions can appear in one slot
only, and furthermore that slot has to be the slot index 0 or the first slot in a format.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_LS_UNIT_MULTIPLE_SLOT</title>
<para>
A load/store unit cannot be used in multiple slots. This error can only be generated
when the TIE compiler has assigned load/store units incorrectly. Hence this is an
internal error and should be reported to Tensilica.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_LS_UNIT_SLOTS</title>
<para>
Number of load/store units cannot accomodate load/store operations in these slots.
Xtensa processor supports upto 2 load/store units for FLIX configurations. With
two load/store units, a FLIX format can have load/store instructions in two slots.
However, with one load/store unit, load/store instructions can appear in one slot
only, and furthermore that slot has to be the slot index 0 or the first slot in a format.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="">TIE_MAC</title>
<para>
MR register file in MAC16 package is special. It cannot be used by user. 
This error is generated if the user tries to use the MR register file.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_MACRO</title>
<para>
Error in using a TIE module. For a list of TIE modules and their usage, see the
TIE language Reference Manual. Some of the specific errors are listed below:
</para>
<list>
<item><itemtext>TIEmul : must have three arguments, 
	last argument that specifies signed multiply must be 1 bit.</itemtext>
</item>
<item><itemtext>TIEmulpp, TIEmac : the arguments specifying negate and sign must be 1 bit.</itemtext>
</item>
<item><itemtext>TIEcsa : must have 4 arguments.</itemtext>
</item>
<item><itemtext>TIEadd : must have 3 arguments, the argument specifying carry in must be 1 bit.</itemtext>
</item>
<item><itemtext>TIEcmp : the first two arguments must be the same width.</itemtext>
</item>
<item><itemtext>TIEmux : number of arguments must be power of 2.</itemtext>
</item>
</list>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_MACRO_SIGNAL_WIDTH</title>
<para>
Incorrect width of argument to a tie module. Restrictions are:
</para>
<list>
<item><itemtext>Select signal of TIEmux must be log2 of the number of data arguments</itemtext>
</item>
<item><itemtext>Each select signal of TIEsel must be width 1.</itemtext>
</item>
</list>
<para>
Note that all immediate operands created using immediate_range, tables, and
the operand construct are defined to be 32 bits wide. If an immediate operand
is being used in the TIE module, please ensure that appropriate bits of the
operand are selected.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="WARN_DEFAULT_OFF">TIE_MULPP_ASSIGNMENT</title>
<para>
This warning is not seen by default. Please run TIE compiler with -warnall flag.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="WARN_DEFAULT_OFF">TIE_MULPP_PARTIAL_PRODUCT_SUM</title>
<para>
This warning is not seen by default. Please run TIE compiler with -warnall flag.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="WARN_DEFAULT_OFF">TIE_MULPP_PARTIAL_PRODUCT_USE</title>
<para>
This warning is not seen by default. Please run TIE compiler with -warnall flag.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_MULTIPLE_ASSIGNMENT</title>
<para>
There are more than one assignments to a wire or output.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_MULT_COPROC</title>
<para>
An instruction can only access states or register files that belong to a single
coprocessor. This restriction exists to ensure that an instruction can generate
a single coprocessor exception.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_NAME_DUP</title>
<para>
Duplicate name found in the same scope. Note that although TIE language is case
sensitive, duplicate name check in a scope is performed in a case-insensitive
way to avoid naming conflicts in tools that read the output of TIE compiler 
generated RTL. For example, the following code will generate an error.
</para>
<para>
state TEST_DUP  32
state Test_Dup  40
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="">TIE_NO_TCTOOLS</title>
<para>
The installation directory for TIE compiler could not be found.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_NOT_DECL</title>
<para>
The variable used in the statements has not been declared as an input or output to
this block. For example, to use a variable inside an operation, the variable
must be declared in the argument list of the operation.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_NOT_DEFINED</title>
<para>
Some variables must be defined before they are used. For example, a state or register
file must be defined before it can be used in an operation.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_NOT_DEFINED_CASE</title>
<para>
Some variables must be defined before they are used. This warning is
issued when a variable only differs by case from another one.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_NOT_FOUND</title>
<para>
A variable used has not been defined.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_NOT_SUPPORTED</title>
<para>
The feature is not supported in this version of TIE language.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_NOT_CONFIGURED</title>
<para>
Certain Xtensa configuration options are required to use some  features of TIE language
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON|WARN_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_NO_ASSIGNMENT</title>
<para>
All outputs of an operation must be assigned to in the body of the operation or semantic.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_NO_READ</title>
<para>
A variable name can appear on the right hand side of an assignment only if it is declared
as an input in the current scope. Outputs of an operation or function can only appear in the
left hand side of an assignment.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON|WARN_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_NO_USE</title>
<para>
The input to an operation or a function has not been used in the body of the operation or function.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="WARN_DEFAULT_OFF">TIE_NO_VALID_INSTR</title>
<para>
There must be a valid instruction with this name. For example, writing a schedule for an instruction
for which there is no implementation (reference, operation, or semantic) is illegal. Note that 
an opcode is not an instruction until it has an implementation in any of these forms.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_NO_WRITE</title>
<para>
A variable name can appear on the left hand side of an assignment only if it is declared
as an output in the current scope. Inputs of an operation or function can only appear in the
right hand side of an assignment.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_OPCODE_DENSITY</title>
<para>
A user TIE instruction can be the default instruction size of 24 bits, or part of a FLIX instruction.
It cannot be defined as a density (16 bit) instruction. If the encoding of an instruction sets the
bits in the instruction word that decodes it as a 16bit instruction, an error is generated.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_OPCODE_ENCODING</title>
<para>
Incorrect encoding for an opcode. For example, the following code will generate an error
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_OPCODE_FIELD_SIZE_ONLY</title>
<para>
Opcode encoding is defined as &lt;field&gt;=&lt;value&gt;, where the field must be defined
precisely in every slot that the opcode belongs to. Using a field that is not 
mapped to specific bits of a slot generates an error. Note that the TIE compiler 
automatically generates encodings for operations. For example, the following
opcode encoding is illegal because the field &quot;fldx&quot; is not fully specified
in the slot &quot;slot1&quot;.
</para>
<para>
field fldx slot1[*]
opcode check fldx=4'd15
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_OPCODE_FIELD_UNDEFINED</title>
<para>
Opcode encoding is defined as &lt;field&gt;=&lt;value&gt;, where the field must be defined
in every slot that the opcode belongs to. Using a field that is not defined
in encoding generates an error. Note that the TIE compiler automatically
generates encodings for operations.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_OPCODE_MULTI_DEF</title>
<para>
An opcode can have only one encoding in a slot. It can have multiple encodings
that apply to different slots. For example, in the following code, since the
fields &quot;x&quot; and &quot;y&quot; are both defined both in slot1, the opcode &quot;check&quot; has multiple
definitions in slot1.
</para>
<para>
field x slot1[21:18]
field y slot1[15:12]
opcode multi x=4'd15
opcode multi y=4'd15
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_OPCODE_NON_INST_SLOT_ONLY</title>
<para>
An instruction can be added to a slot with the &quot;slot_opcodes&quot; statement only if
it is a valid instruction, i.e. it has a valid implementation.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_OPCODE_NO_ICLASS</title>
<para>
An opcode must have an iclass to be implemented in a reference or semantic. An
iclass defines the input and output operands of the instruction. Note that an instruction written
as an operation combines the iclass and reference.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_OPCODE_NO_IMPL</title>
<para>
An instruction that is defined with an opcode and a iclass must have an implementation
in the form of a reference or a semantic, or both. Note that an instruction written
as an operation combines the iclass and reference.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_OPCODE_NO_SLOT</title>
<para>
All instructions must belong to at least one slot. By default, all user TIE instructions
appear in the 24 bit &quot;Inst&quot; slot. If the user has a FLIX format, an instruction must be
added to a FLIX format with a slot_opcodes statement.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_OPCODE_OPERAND_OVERLAP</title>
<para>
The field used for encoding an instruction is the same as that used for encoding an operand 
of an instruction. In the following example, the &quot;r&quot; field is used for encoding the opcode
as well the operand arr.
</para>
<para>
opcode MYOP r=4'b0000 CUST0
iclass MYOP { MYOP } { out arr , in ars }
</para>
<para>
Error: (TIE_OPCODE_OPERAND_OVERLAP),
        For instruction MYOP in slot Inst, opcode MYOP overlaps
        with field r used in operand arr
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_OPCODE_OVERLAP</title>
<para>
The encodings of all opcodes in a slot must be disjoint. For example, in the following
code, the encoding of MYOP1 and MYOP2 overlap.
</para>
<para>
field op2b op2[1:0]
opcode MYOP1 op2=4'b1111 CUST0
opcode MYOP2 op2b=2'b11  CUST0
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_OPCODE_PARENT_AMBIGUOUS</title>
<para>
Encoding of an opcode in a slot is not fully specified.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_OPCODE_PARENT_UNDEFINED</title>
<para>
Parent opcode in an opcode encoding is not defined.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_OPCODE_REQ_SLOT</title>
<para>
An opcode that is requested in a slot with a slot_opcodes statement is not be
defined in that slot. For an opcode to be defined in a slot, all fields 
needed to encode the opcode and its operands must be defined in that slot.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_OPCODE_UNIQUE_SLOT</title>
<para>
A opcode can be defined in a slot by using a simple definition, or full
encoding as shown below
</para>
<para>
opcode MYOP slot1 // simple definition, encoding not specified
</para>
<para>
OR
</para>
<para>
field fldx slot1[21:18]
opcode MYOP fldx=4'd15  // encoding specified
</para>
<para>
However mixing the two formats is illegal as shown below.
</para>
<para>
opcode MYOP slot1 fldy=2'b11 //illegal
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_OPERAND_AR_ILL</title>
<para>
User cannot define operands on AR register file. 
The only allowed operands on AR regfile are: ars, art, arr.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_OPERAND_CORE_OPERAND</title>
<para>
Xtensa core operands such as &quot;ars&quot; cannot be redefined by user TIE.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_OPERAND_OPERAND_OVERLAP</title>
<para>
An instruction has two operands whose encoding fields overlap.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_OPERAND_RHS</title>
<para>
Operand appears on the left hand side of assignment.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_OPERAND_MAP_ARG_ERR</title>
<para>
The argument of operand_map construct contains error. 
The error is that the operand, operation, or operation argument is missing in the TIE file.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_OPERATION_AMBIGUOUS_NAME</title>
<para>
Conflicting variable name in an operation. For example, in the following code,
the operation TESTDUP has an input VAddr, which could be the interface or the
state.
</para>
<para>
state VAddr  32 
operation TESTDUP { out AR a } { in VAddr }
</para>
<para>
Error: (TIE_OPERATION_AMBIGUOUS_NAME),
        &quot;VAddr&quot; is ambiguous in operation's body, could
        be state or interface
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_OPERATION_ARG_AMBIGUOUS</title>
<para>
Conflicting argument name in an operation. An argument cannot have the same
name as the operation because the name of the operation is an implicit input
to the operation with a constant value of 1.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_OPERATION_ARG_DIR</title>
<para>
The direction of the operation argument is wrong. Immediate operands, 
immediate ranges, tables must be input operands.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_OPERATION_AMBIGUOUS_TYPE</title>
<para>
Conflicting argument type in an operation. Valid argument types are register 
files, operands, tables. For example, in the following code,
</para>
<para>
regfile XR 8 8 xr
table XR 1 1 { 0 }
operation BAR { out XR a }
</para>
<para>
Error: (TIE_OPERATION_AMBIGUOUS_TYPE),
        Argument &quot;a&quot; has ambiguous type XR, could be regfile or table
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_OPERATION_ARG_WIRE_CONFLICT</title>
<para>
Wire names in the operation body cannot be the same as the operation
argument.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_OPERATION_CASE_CONFLICT</title>
<para>
Operation name and opcode names must match exactly if both opcode and 
operation is provided. If an operation name matches an opcode name
but varies only in case, this is an error.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_OPERATION_CONFLICT</title>
<para>
An instruction can be defined as an operation, or as an opcode/iclass/reference, 
but not both.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_OPERATION_CORE_STATE</title>
<para>
User defined operations cannot read Xtensa core states. The only exception is
the state SAR, which holds the shift amount for some shift operations.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_OPERATION_DUPLICATE_ARG</title>
<para>
Same operation argument name declared twice. Operation argument names must be 
unique in a case insensitive manner.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_OPERATION_DUP_OPERAND</title>
<para>
An operation argument type can be a register file name, or an operand name.
If the argument is written as a register file, then an operand will be
generated for it. If it is written as an operand, then it will be used
directly. In this latter case, each operand used as an argument must
be unique.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_OPERATION_IMPLICIT_OPERAND</title>
<para>
There are some implicit operands in the Xtensa core which read a register
file but the index is fixed or not encoded in the instruction. These 
operands cannot be used in user TIE operations.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_OPERATION_INTERFACE_DIR</title>
<para>
Interface declared in the operation state-interface list does not match the
direction in the interface definition. For example, in the following code,
the interface MemDataIn32 is declared as an output of the operation MYOP,
which is incorrect since MemDataIn32 is an input interface.
</para>
<para>
operation MYOP { out AR d, in AR p } { out VAddr, out MemDataIn32 }
</para>
<para>
Error: (TIE_OPERATION_INTERFACE_DIR),
        Operation MYOP, interface MemDataIn32 declared
        as out but it should be in
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_OPERATION_INVALID_KILL</title>
<para>
Output operands of operations can have be updated conditionally. An implicit output named
&lt;output_name&gt;_kill can be assigned in the operation body. If this output is true, the 
update of the register operand is killed. To assign a kill signal in an operation
body, there should be a valid output declared in the operation argument.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_OPERATION_INVALID_STATE_KILL</title>
<para>
Output states of operations can have be updated conditionally. An implicit output named
&lt;state_name&gt;_kill can be assigned in the operation body. If this output is true, the 
update of the state is killed. To assign a kill signal in an operation body, 
the state should be declared as an output of the operation.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_OPERATION_INVALID_INTERFACE_KILL</title>
<para>
An operation reading or writing a TIE queue can use the &quot;_KILL&quot; interfaces to 
conditionally read or write the queue. In this case, the queue itself must be an input
or output of the operation.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="">TIE_OPERATION_NO_DEP</title>
<para>
The input to the operation is not being used to generate any of the outputs. This
is determined by analyzing the body of the operation.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_OPERATION_NO_SEMANTIC</title>
<para>
An operation usually contains the arguments and a body that represents the 
implementation of the instruction. In the case where the operation is also
implemented in a semantic, the operation body can be left blank. However,
the operation must have at least one implementation in either form.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_OPERATION_OPERAND_REGFILE_NUM</title>
<para>
The number of arguments in the operation that reads a register file
exceeds the number of entries in the register file. For example, an
operation cannot read 5 inputs from a register file with 4 entries.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_OPERATION_POINTER_ARG</title>
<para>
An operation argument can be declared as a pointer. This is usually
done when writing load/store operations. The pointer argument is
declared as a pointer to a register file or operand type, which means that the
address to the data in memory for that register file is stored in the
pointer. Pointers are always 32 bits and kept in the AR register file.
Pointer arguments are allowed for register arguments only. For example, 
in the following code, the operation MYOP declares a pointer to an immediate
range, which is illegal.
</para>
<para>
operation MYOP { out AR a, in IMMRANGE *b} {out VAddr, in MemDataIn32}
</para>
<para>
Error: (TIE_OPERATION_POINTER_ARG),
        Operation argument b cannot be a pointer. Pointers
        allowed only for regfile arguments.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_OPERATION_REF_OPERAND</title>
<para>
When an operation argument type is an operand, the argument name should still
be used in the operation body instead of the operand name. For example, in
the following code, the valid variable names in the body of MYOP are the 
arguments &quot;a&quot; and &quot;b&quot;,  and not the operand names &quot;ars&quot; and &quot;arr&quot;.
</para>
<para>
operation MYOP { out arr a, in ars b } {}
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_OPERATION_REQUIRES_STATE</title>
<para>
An operation can be required to use a certain state.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_OPERATION_SAME_ARG_TYPE</title>
<para>
In an operation, argument types and names must be unique, i.e. an argument name
cannot be the same as the type name of another argument. For example, in the
following code, the operation MYOP has an argument type IMMOP and an argument
name IMMOP.
</para>
<para>
operation MYOP { out AR IMMOP, in IMMOP b } {}
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_OPERATION_UNKNOWN_ARG</title>
<para>
Argument type in operation declaration is unknown, i.e. it is not a register file,
operand, immediate range or table.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_OPERATION_VERIFY_INVALID</title>
<para>
Argument in operation's state interface list is unknown, i.e. it is not a state
or interface.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_OPERATION_VERIFY_MISSING</title>
<para>
A state or interface declared as an input or output in the declaration is not
being read or assigned to in the operation body.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_OPERATION_VERIFY_UNEXPECTED</title>
<para>
A state or interface that is being assigned to or read from in the operation
body has not been declared as an output or input in the declaration.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_OPERATOR_PROTO_ARG</title>
<para>
The argument of the proto used in operator construct is wrong. It is 
possibly because:
1. argument of direction inout is used. 
2. number of arguments does not match specification.
3. immediate values are used in argument.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_OPERATOR_PROTO_CASE</title>
<para>
The proto used in operator construct and the defined proto are different in case.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_OPERATOR_UNDEFINED_PROTO</title>
<para>
The proto used in operator construct is not defined.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_OPERATOR_UNKNOWN</title>
<para>
The operator type is not in the supported list.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="MSG_DEFAULT_OFF">TIE_OPER_AND_SEM</title>
<para>
An instruction can have two implementations in TIE language. One is the 
operation or reference, and the other is the semantic. A semantic is
usually written to share the implementation of more than one instruction
in the same module. If both implementations exist, the TIE compiler 
generates netlists and scripts to formally verify that the two are
equivalent. The user is encouraged to a tool like Verplex or Formality
to formally check the two implementations.
</para>
<para>
This message is not shown by default. It can be seen when running TIE
compiler with -msgall flag.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PREDEFINED</title>
<para>
User TIE cannot define an instruction that is predefined in the Xtensa core.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PRINT_ARGUMENT_MISMATCH</title>
<para>
This error occurs when the conversions ( i.e. %d, %x, etc. ) and the formatting arguments given to a TIEprint
module do not correlate. Make sure you have the same number of conversions in your formatting string as
arguments in the argument list.
</para>
<para>
Examples:
</para>
<list>
<item><itemtext>This TIEprint has two conversions specified but only one argument: 
<code>TIEprint( &quot;Two conversions, %d, %08x, one argument\n&quot;, address );</code></itemtext>
</item>
<item><itemtext>This TIEprint has one conversion, but two arguments:     
<code>TIEprint( &quot;One conversion, %d, two arguments\n&quot;, address, align );</code></itemtext>
</item>
</list>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PRINT_ARGUMENT_TOO_WIDE</title>
<para>
Arguments to TIEprint modules must be &lt;= 32 bits. If an expression is used as an argument in a TIEprint module
the result of this expression must be &lt;= 32 bits. If you want to print a variable or expression that is longer than
32 bits use bit selects to split the argument into pieces smaller than 32 bits.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PRINT_ILLEGAL_FORMATTING</title>
<para>
Conversions in a TIEprint module formatting string must be in an allowed format. Currently allowed conversions are;
</para>
<list>
<item><itemtext>%d: 
<strong>signed decimal</strong></itemtext>
</item>
<item><itemtext>%x: 
<strong>unsigned hexadecimal</strong></itemtext>
</item>
<item><itemtext>%u: 
<strong>unsigned decimal</strong></itemtext>
</item>
<item><itemtext>%[0-9][0-9]*[d,u,x]: 
<strong>[0-9]* characters printed in representation given by [d,u,x]. 
If [0-9] is present at the beginning of the conversion padded with leading characters based on the number given.</strong></itemtext>
</item>
</list>
<para>
Please review all conversions and make sure that they match the syntax given above.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PRINT_ILLEGAL_VARIABLE</title>
<para>
An illegal variable or expression is used in a TIEprint module. The offending expression will be printed along with the error message.
Please review the expression and make sure all variables are legal in the current scope.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PRINT_TOO_MANY_ARGUMENTS</title>
<para>
You are only allowed 32 arguments to a single TIEprint module. Please use more than one TIEprint module if you wish 
to print more than 32 arguments.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PRINT_QUALIFIER_TOO_WIDE</title>
<para>
The qualifier in a TIEprint module must be &lt;= 32 bits wide.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROPERTY_ARG_COUNT_MISMATCH</title>
<para>
The number of in, out and inout arguments that the two protos should be the same.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROPERTY_ARG_DUP</title>
<para>
The argument appears more than once in the argument list.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROPERTY_EXPORT_SAME</title>
<para>
The export property of some states should be identical.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON|WARN_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROPERTY_ILLEGAL_ARG</title>
<para>
The property has an illegal argument, or the argument is not recognized by TIE compiler.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROPERTY_MISSING</title>
<para>
The name, attribute, or the arguments is missing in the property.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROPERTY_NONFLIX_INSTRUCTION</title>
<para>
Some Xtensa core instructions are not allowed in a FLIX format.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROPERTY_WRONG_ARGS</title>
<para>
The arguments of the property is wrong. It may be because:
1. The number of arguments is not expected.
2. For shared_semantic property, same slot index appear in multiple sharing groups.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROPERTY_UNKNOWN</title>
<para>
The property is not recognized by TIE compiler.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROPERTY_UNKNOWN_ATTR</title>
<para>
The property has an unknown attribute.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROTO_ADDRESS_POINTER</title>
<para>
A load or store prototype is written to indicate to the compiler how
to get data from the register file to memory and vice versa. The
proto must conform to strict rules for the compiler to use it.
The second argument of the proto must be a pointer to the data
type in the register file for which the proto is being written.
The following are examples of correct protos
</para>
<para>
regfile XR 64 16 xr
ctype data64 64 64 XR
</para>
<para>
proto data64_loadi  { out data64 d, in data64 *p, in immediate o } {} { //load instruction }
proto data64_storei { in  data64 d, in data64 *p, in immediate o } {} { //store instruction }
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="WARN_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROTO_ADDRESS_UPDATE</title>
<para>
A load or store prototype is written to indicate to the compiler how
to get data from the register file to memory and vice versa. The
proto must conform to strict rules for the compiler to use it.
There are two categories of load/store protos with immediate offset.
The loadi/storei protos don't update the address register with the
address computed, and the loadiu/storeiu protos update the address
register with the computed address. The instructions used in the
protos must be appropriate. Following are examples of some illegal protos
</para>
<para>
regfile XR 64 16 xr
ctype data64 64 64 XR
</para>
<para>
//incorrect loadi proto, address pointer p gets updated
proto data64_loadi  { out data64 d, in data64 *p, in immediate o } {} 
{
   ADDI p, p, o;
   //load instruction with p as address pointer
}
</para>
<para>
//incorrect loadiu proto, address pointer p does not get updated
proto data64_loadi  { out data64 d, inout data64 *p, in immediate o } {} 
{
   //load instruction with p as address pointer
}
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON|WARN_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROTO_ARG_DIR</title>
<para>
A prototype has one or more instructions which are called with the
arguments to the proto. The direction of the proto arguments should
match the direction of the operands of the instruction in the proto
body. For example, in the following code, the move prototype has
an input argument &quot;d&quot; and an output argument &quot;v&quot;, but in the proto
body the move instruction MOV.S has been called with the argument
&quot;d&quot; and &quot;v&quot; as the output and input argument respectively.
</para>
<para>
regfile XR 64 16 xr
ctype data64 64 64 XR
</para>
<para>
operation MOV.S { out XR a, in XR b } { assign a = b; }
</para>
<para>
proto data64_move { out data64 d, in data64 v } {} { MOV.S v, d; }
</para>
<para>
Note that protos are automatically generated by TIE compiler 
for all operations.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROTO_KILL_ARG_DIR</title>
<para>
If a proto uses an instruction whose output has a conditional kill, the
corresponding proto argument must be an &quot;inout&quot; instead of &quot;out&quot;. This
is because the compiler needs to recognize the read-modify-write nature
of the operation. For example, in the following code, the proto for the
conditional move instruction MOV.T must have the output argument &quot;d&quot;
declared as inout.
</para>
<para>
regfile XR 64 16 xr
ctype data64 64 64 XR
</para>
<para>
operation MOV.T { out XR a, in XR b } { assign a = b; assign a_kill = b[0]; }
</para>
<para>
proto data64_move { inout data64 d, in data64 v } {} { MOV.T d, v; }
</para>
<para>
Note that when TIE compiler automatically generates protos for all operations
with the correct argument direction taking into consideration the kill.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROTO_ARG_DUP</title>
<para>
Duplicate argument in proto.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROTO_ARG_FIELD_DEFINED</title>
<para>
Input argument field of the proto was used as an output argument in an instruction in the body.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="WARN_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROTO_ARG_FIELD_NO_USE</title>
<para>
Input argument field of the proto has not been used in the body.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROTO_ARG_OUT_FIELD_USE</title>
<para>
Output argument field of the proto is used as an input.
There are a few cases where it is useful to use ANY register in such
a way that it generates a constant.  If this is desired, as in using
\&quot;XOR b, a, a\&quot; to generate 0 in b, use a temporary.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROTO_ARG_OUT_FIELD_NO_DEF</title>
<para>
Output argument field of the proto has not been used in the body.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="">TIE_PROTO_ARG_OUT_FIELD_UNDECLARED</title>
<para>
Input argument field of the proto has not been used in the body.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="WARN_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROTO_ARG_NO_USE</title>
<para>
Input argument or temporary argument of proto has not been used in the body.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="WARN_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROTO_ARG_OUT</title>
<para>
Output argument of proto has issues. It may not be used in the proto body, 
or assigned value multiple times in the proto body.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROTO_ARG_ORDER</title>
<para>
A load and store prototype is written to indicate to the compiler how
to get data from the register file to memory and vice versa. A move
prototype tells the compiler how to copy data between two registers.
Protos can also be written to convert between two data types.
These protos must conform to strict rules for the compiler to use it.
For a list of all the protos, please refer to TIE language Ref Manual.
</para>
<list>
<item><itemtext>*For a load proto, the first argument must be an output of the ctype.</itemtext>
</item>
<item><itemtext>*For a store proto, the first argument must be an input of the cytpe.</itemtext>
</item>
<item><itemtext>*For a move proto, the first argument must be an output of ctype.</itemtext>
</item>
<item><itemtext>*For load/store proto, the second argument must be an input of type
pointer to the ctype. This specifies the address.</itemtext>
</item>
<item><itemtext>*For a move proto, the first argument must be an input of the cytpe.</itemtext>
</item>
<item><itemtext>*If a third argument exists for a load/store proto, it must be an 
immediate for the loadi/storei proto, or a ctype mapped to AR (uint32, int32)
for the indexed proto loadx/storex.</itemtext>
</item>
</list>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROTO_ARG_POINTER</title>
<para>
Some ctypes when used in protos can only be pointers. These are 64 bit data
types &quot;uint64&quot; and &quot;int64&quot;, as well as &quot;void&quot;.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROTO_ARG_STRUCT</title>
<para>
Struct ctypes are not allowed in instruction protos.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROTO_ARG_TYPE</title>
<para>
Proto arguments that are register operands must be valid ctypes defined for
that register file. Also, note that &quot;char&quot; cannot be used as a proto argument,
&quot;uint8&quot; or &quot;int8&quot; should be used, due to the ambiguity of the behavior of 
&quot;char&quot; being signed or unsigned.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROTO_CODEARG_CASE_FIELD</title>
<para>
In a proto, a code argument must have only valid fields specified for it.
This error is issued when a field of the same name exists, but differs in
case from the field specified.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROTO_CODEARG_DECL</title>
<para>
Argument used in proto body has not been declared in the proto declaration.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROTO_CODEARG_NONIMM_OFFSET</title>
<para>
Immediate constant offsets can be added to instruction arguments in proto body
only for immediate operands. For example, in the following code, the argument
&quot;c + 1&quot; for the immediate operand is legal, but the argument &quot;b + 2&quot; for the
register operand is illegal.
</para>
<para>
operation my.add { in AR a, in AR b, in simm8 off } {} { assign a = b + offset; }
</para>
<para>
proto my_add_3 { out uint32 a, in uint32 b, in immediate c } { } { my.add a, b + 2, c + 1; }
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROTO_CODEARG_NO_FIELD</title>
<para>
In a proto, a code argument with ctypes that represents a single register may not have a field specified for it.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROTO_CODEARG_REQUIRED_FIELD</title>
<para>
In a proto, a code argument with ctypes that represents multiple registers that are not a register view must have a field specifier to identify which register to use.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROTO_CODEARG_INVALID_FIELD</title>
<para>
In a proto, a code argument must have only valid fields specified for it.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROTO_CODEARG_NUM</title>
<para>
The number of arguments to an instruction in a proto body must match the
number of arguments in the instruction. For example, in the following
code, the proto my_add_3 calls the instruction &quot;my.add&quot; with only 2
arguments instead of 3.
</para>
<para>
operation my.add { in AR a, in AR b, in simm8 off } {} { assign a = b + offset; }
</para>
<para>
proto my_add_3 { out uint32 a, in uint32 b } { } { my.add a, b; }
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROTO_CODEARG_REGFILE</title>
<para>
When a proto input or output argument of a certain ctype is passed to an instruction in its body,
the underlying register file of the ctype must be the register file of the instruction input/output.
For example, in the following code, the proto &quot;my_add_3&quot; calls the instruction &quot;my.add&quot; with the
output argument a, which in the proto is mapped to the AR register file, but in the instruction
is mapped to the XR register file.
</para>
<para>
regfile XR 64 16 xr
ctype data64 64 64 XR
</para>
<para>
operation my.add { in XR a, in XR b, in simm8 off } {} { assign a = b + offset; }
</para>
<para>
proto my_add_3 { out uint32 a, in data64 b, in immediate o } { } { my.add a, b, o; }
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROTO_CODEARG_TEMP_OFFSET</title>
<para>
A proto can have temporary variables to hold intermediate results when the body
contains more than one instruction. However, when using the temporary variables
in the body, no offset can be added. For example, in the following code, the
temporary variable &quot;x&quot; cannot be used as &quot;x+2&quot;.
</para>
<para>
proto my_add_4 { out uint32 a, in uint32 b } { uint32 x}
{
  //generate x
  my.add a, b, x + 2;    
}
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROTO_CODEARG_TYPE</title>
<para>
The argument type of the proto argument used as an input or output operand of
an instruction in the body must match the operand type in the instruction.
For example, in the following code, the proto &quot;my_add_3&quot; calls the instruction
&quot;my.add&quot; with the third argument as &quot;b&quot; which is a register operand and does
not match the immediate operand of instruction &quot;my.add&quot;.
</para>
<para>
operation my.add { in AR a, in AR b, in simm8 off } {} { assign a = b + offset; }
</para>
<para>
proto my_add_3 { out uint32 a, in uint32 b } { } { my.add a, b, b; }
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="WARN_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROTO_CODEARG_BASE_ADDRESS</title>
<para>
In a load/store proto, the second argument to the proto is the address pointer.
This is the argument that should be used as the base address input to the load/store
instruction in the proto body. For example, in the following code, the address
argument p is not being used as the base address input p to the load instruction
L32I.
</para>
<para>
regfile XR 64 16 xr
ctype data64 64 64 XR
operation load_add { out XR d, in XR *p, in XR a } { out VAddr, in MemDataIn32 } 
{ assign VAddr = p; assign d = MemDataIn32 + a; }
</para>
<para>
proto load_add64 { out data64 d, in data64 *p, in data64 p1 } {} { load_add d, p1, p; }
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="WARN_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROTO_CODE_ADDRESS</title>
<para>
The load/store instructions used in load/store protos must conform to strict
addressing rules. The address must be generated from any of the following:
</para>
<list>
<item><itemtext>VAddr = AR register operand</itemtext>
</item>
<item><itemtext>VAddr = AR register operand + immediate offset for loadi/storei</itemtext>
</item>
<item><itemtext>VAddr = AR register operand + AR register operand for loadx/storex</itemtext>
</item>
</list>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROTO_CORE_PROTO</title>
<para>
A user defined proto cannot have the same name as an Xtensa core proto.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROTO_CTYPE_CONFLICT</title>
<para>
A proto name is the same as a ctype name, which is not legal.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROTO_ILLEGAL_COPROC</title>
<para>
Load and store protos can only generate one coprocessor exception.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROTO_INSTR_CODEARG_OFFSET</title>
<para>
All instructions in user TIE have a corresponding proto. This is automatically
generated by the TIE compiler. If the user writes an instruction proto, the
argument in the proto body must come directly from the proto arguments. No
offsets are allowed.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROTO_INSTR_CODEARG_SEQUENCE</title>
<para>
All instructions in user TIE have a corresponding proto. This is automatically
generated by the TIE compiler. If the user writes an instruction proto, the
arguments in the proto body must have the same sequence as the arguments in 
proto arguments.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROTO_INSTR_NUM_ARGUMENTS</title>
<para>
All instructions in user TIE have a corresponding proto. This is automatically
generated by the TIE compiler. If the user writes an instruction proto, the
number of arguments of the proto must be the same as the number of arguments in 
the proto body.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROTO_INVALID_OPCODE</title>
<para>
The opcode name used inside the proto body is not a valid instruction.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROTO_LOADSTORE_DATA</title>
<para>
The load/store instructions used in load/store protos must conform to strict
rules. The memory data in a load instruction must be directly assigned to
the output register. Similarly, the memory data in a store instruction should
be directly assigned from the input register.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROTO_MEMSIZE</title>
<para>
The load/store instructions used in load/store protos must conform to strict
rules. The size of the memory data (MemDataIn/MemDataOut) must be at least
the size of the ctype. For example, a single load instruction that uses MemDataIn32
cannot be used in the loadi proto for a ctype that is 40 bits wide. Note that,
two such loads in the loadi proto would be legal.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROTO_MISSING</title>
<para>
All instructions must have a corresponding proto, either written by user or
generated automatically by TIE compiler. In some cases, the user has to 
explicitly write instruction protos. For example, if a register file used
by the instruction has multiple ctypes, none of which could be identified
as a default ctype for the register file, then TIE compiler will not generate
the instruction proto.
</para>
<para>
Similarly, all ctypes must have at least loadi/storei/move prototypes. These
can be generated automatically by the TIE compiler in most cases. However,
in some cases TIE compiler cannot do it due to restrictions. For example, if
a ctype of size 64 bits exists in a Xtensa configuration with memory size
of 32 bits, TIE compiler will not automatically generate a load/store proto
with two load/store instructions.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROTO_NO_CODE</title>
<para>
Blank proto body.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROTO_NO_TEMP</title>
<para>
No temporary variables are allowed for certain protos.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROTO_NUM_ARGS</title>
<para>
Some protos can only have a strict number of arguments. 
For example, loadi/storei protos cannot have more than 3 arguments.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="WARN_DEFAULT_OFF">TIE_PROTO_NUM_TEMP</title>
<para>
Some protos can only have a strict number of temporary variables.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="WARN_DEFAULT_OFF">TIE_PROTO_OLD_RURWUR_REF</title>
<para>
A proto is using an old style RUR/WUR instruction which is being
automatically converted to the new style.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROTO_ONE_OPCODE</title>
<para>
Instruction proto (one proto per instruction) which has the same
name as the instruction must use only one opcode.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROTO_OPERATION_NAME_CASE</title>
<para>
Proto names and operation names cannot be different only in case, or different using '.' or '_' letters. They can be exactly the same or totally different. 
If proto names and operation names are exactly the same, the proto is an instruction proto containing only the operation.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROTO_TEMP_TYPE</title>
<para>
Proto temporaries must be have valid ctypes.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROTO_TEMP_TYPE_CASE</title>
<para>
Proto temporaries must be have valid ctypes. This error is issued when 
a ctype of the same name exists, but differs in case from the ctype specified.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROTO_TEMP_WRONG_CTYPE</title>
<para>
For load/store protos, the type of the only temporary variable 
cannot share the same register file  as the ctype intended to load or store.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="WARN_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROTO_UNUSED</title>
<para>
The proto is unused by XCC. For rtom and rtor converstion protos, 
XCC does not use the conversion proto if the source ctype is one of the following:
uint8, int8, uint16, int16.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROTO_WRONG_CONVERT</title>
<para>
Conversion protos are written to convert a datatype to another.
They are of the following form:
</para>
<list>
<item><itemtext>&lt;ctype_from&gt;_rtor_&lt;ctype_to&gt;, for both datatypes are in registers.</itemtext>
</item>
<item><itemtext>&lt;ctype_from&gt;_mtor_&lt;ctype_to&gt;, for converting ctype_from in memory to ctype_to in register.</itemtext>
</item>
<item><itemtext>&lt;ctype_from&gt;_rtom_&lt;ctype_to&gt;, for converting ctype_from in register to ctype_to in memory.</itemtext>
</item>
</list>
<para>
Both ctypes must be valid in the above protos.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="WARN_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PROTO_WRONG_MOVE</title>
<para>
Move prototype must use instruction that does a strict register to register move without 
any computation or conditional move. This analysis of move instruction used in the proto
can be done by analyzing a shared semantic.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_REGFILE_CORE_REGFILE</title>
<para>
An Xtensa core register file (such as AR, BR, MR) cannot be redefined in user TIE. Also,
user tie cannot redefine the number of callee saved entries in the core register files.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_REGFILE_ILLEGAL_DEPTH</title>
<para>
Number of entries in a register file must be power of 2 to generate efficient addressing bits
for indexing.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_REGFILE_ILLEGAL_SNAME</title>
<para>
A register file &quot;short name&quot; is used in all software tools. This name must be upto 6 characters
long and cannot contain &quot;.&quot; in it. This is to ensure correctness of all s/w tools including
debugger.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_REGFILE_MAX_DEPTH</title>
<para>
User defined register files can have a maximum of 1024 entries.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="WARN_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_REGFILE_DEPTH</title>
<para>
User defined register files can have up to a maximum of 1024 entries. However,
register files with more than 128 entries require an enhanced version of the XCC 
compiler to compile C/C++ programs targeted for such a TIE design. Using the 
default version of the XCC compiler that you have downloaded as part of the software 
tools will result in an error. If you plan to use register files with more than 
128 entries, please contact your Tensilica support engineer to request the enhanced 
version of the XCC compiler.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_REGFILE_MAX_NUMBER</title>
<para>
The XCC compiler has a restriction on number of register files. A total of 24 register
files can exist in the core (Xtensa + user TIE).
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_REGFILE_MULTI_DEFAULT_CTYPE</title>
<para>
Register file has multiple default ctypes defined. Only one ctype can be specified as default.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_REGFILE_NO_CTYPE</title>
<para>
All register files must have at least one datatype (ctype) associated with it
to be recognized by the compiler.
If a register file is declared in user tie and no ctype is added, the TIE
compiler creates a default one with the same name as the register file, if it
can. There is currently no way to have a register file that is not recognized
by the compiler.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_REGFILE_NO_LOADSTORE</title>
<para>
All register files must have load and store instructions to read and write the
contents to memory.  If a register file is added in user tie and no load/store
instructions are created, the TIE compiler will automatically generate the
load store instructions if it can.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_REGFILE_NO_READ_PORT</title>
<para>
All register files must have at least one read port, i.e. at least one use/read
of the register file.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_REGFILE_NO_WRITE_PORT</title>
<para>
All register files must have at least one write port, i.e. at least one def/write
to the register file.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_REGFILE_PROTO_GENERATION</title>
<para>
All register files must have a datatype associated with it along with
loadi/storei protos to read/write it from memory. TIE compiler will
automatically generate the ctype and protos, and the load/store
instructions. The load/store instructions generated automatically
are called &quot;ld.REGFILE&quot; and &quot;st.REGFILE&quot;. If user manually writes
instructions/operations that are named the same as these, then
TIE compiler expects them to be the correct load/store instructions
that can be used by the proto.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="WARN_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_REGFILE_SIZE_GT_PIF</title>
<para>
All register files must have a datatype associated with it along with
loadi/storei protos to read/write it from memory. TIE compiler will
automatically generate the ctype and protos, and the load/store instructions.
The case where it cannot automatically generate the load/store instructions
is when the memory width  of the processor is less than the width of the
register file. In this case, the TIE compiler will not automatically
generate multiple load/stores.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_REGFILE_SNAME_DEFINED</title>
<para>
The shortname for the register file is already defined for another register file.
Shortnames, used by s/w tools, must be unique.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_REGFILE_SNAME_RESERVED</title>
<para>
Shortnames used by Xtensa core register files are reserved and cannot be used by user TIE.
These are &quot;sp fp i l L r a b m&quot;.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_REGFILE_NUMERIC_SNAME</title>
<para>
A shortname cannot end with a number. This is because register index is added to the
shortname for describing an entry in the register file and a short name such as
&quot;r1&quot; can generate &quot;r10&quot; for index 0, which cannot be distinguished from a short
name &quot;r&quot; index 10.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_REGFILE_NUM_CALLEE_SAVED</title>
<para>
If not specified, all the register file entries in a register file are caller saved, i.e.
the entire register file is saved before calling a function, and restored upon returning.
The user can override this by specifying the number of callee saved register file entries.
This number must be between 0 and (number of entries - 1). If a register file has N entries
and M are callee saved, the first N - M entries are caller saved, and the last M entries
are callee saved. The first entry must be caller saved.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_REGFILE_SREG_CONFLICT</title>
<para>
A register file name cannot be the same as a special register in the Xtensa core. This
is to avoid name conflict in s/w tools such as debugger.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_REGFILE_STATE_CONFLICT</title>
<para>
Register file and state names must be unique, to avoid name conflict in s/w tools such as debugger.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_REGFILE_FIELD_CONFLICT</title>
<para>
Register file and field names must be unique, if the field is used in operands.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_REGFILE_WIDTH</title>
<para>
The maximum allowed width of register file is 1024 bits.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_REGFILE_USE_DEF</title>
<para>
There are some restrictions on use/def stages on register files. The earliest use
stage of a read port of a register file must be less than the 
maximum def stage among all write ports. For example, the following combination of
use/def stages is illegal: use ( 3, 4) , def ( 1 ), where the stages are numbered
from E(1) and up.
</para>
<para>
In addition, for AR register file, the earliest use stage must be 2 or less.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_SCHED_COPROCESSOR_CONFLICT</title>
<para>
If an instruction accesses state/register/tieports of a coprocessor, tie compiler
automatically generates logic for the instruction to throw a coprocessor exception
if the corresponding bit is disabled in the state CPENABLE. To do so, it adds
CPENABLE as an input to the instruction and a use to the schedule. If a schedule
already exists, and is shared by several instructions whose automatic CPENABLE
use stage, don't match, the user is advised to break up the schedule.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_SCHEDULE_CORE_SCHEDULE</title>
<para>
Schedule name conflicts with a predefined schedule in Xtensa core.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_SCHED_DUPLICATE_OPCODE</title>
<para>
Opcode names in list of schedule must be unique.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_SCHED_ILLEGAL_DEF_NAME</title>
<para>
The def name in the schedule is not an output operand/state for any opcodes 
in the schedule.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_SCHED_ILLEGAL_DEF_STAGE</title>
<para>
Register operands and states can be written in stage 1 (E) and up. Interfaces
such as VAddr and MemDataOut have fixed def stages, which are E and M respectively. 
TIE output queues have fixed def stage of M, and TIE lookup output has def stage
as defined in the lookup.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_SCHED_ILLEGAL_USE_NAME</title>
<para>
The use name in the schedule is not an input operand/state for any opcodes 
in the schedule.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_SCHED_ILLEGAL_USE_STAGE</title>
<para>
Register operands and states can be read in stage 1 (E) and up. Interfaces
such as MemDataIn have fixed use stage (M).  TIE input queues have fixed use stage of M, 
import wires have a fixed use stage of E, and TIE lookup input has use stage as defined in the lookup.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_SCHED_INCORRECT_STAGE</title>
<para>
Interfaces such as VAddr, MemData and TIE queues, lookups and import wires have fixed stages
for reading and writing them. These stages cannot be changed by writing a different schedule
for use/def for a particular opcode. The fixed stages are:
</para>
<list>
<item><itemtext>VAddr : def E</itemtext>
</item>
<item><itemtext>MemDataIn and MemDataOut : use M and def M respectively.</itemtext>
</item>
<item><itemtext>TIE Queue : use M and def M for input and output queues respectively.</itemtext>
</item>
<item><itemtext>TIE lookup : use and def as defined in the lookup.</itemtext>
</item>
<item><itemtext>import wire : use E.</itemtext>
</item>
</list>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_SCHED_INVALID</title>
<para>
The schedule defined for an output cannot be achieved based on the schedule of
inputs and wires in the operation or semantic. For example, in the following
code, the output &quot;d&quot; of the instruction &quot;LOAD.ADD&quot; cannot be defined before the 
M stage because d depends on MemDataIn32, which has a use of M. The schedule
with &quot;def d 1&quot; is therefore invalid.
</para>
<para>
operation LOAD.ADD { out AR d, in AR *p, in AR b } { out VAddr, in MemDataIn32 } 
{
    assign VAddr = p;
    assign d = MemDataIn32 + b;
}
schedule loadadd { LOAD.ADD } { use b 1; use p 1; def d 1; }
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_SCHED_LATENCY</title>
<para>
The maximum latency of an instruction is determined by the Xtensa configuration and
cannot be exceeded when writing a schedule.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_SCHED_MIN_DEF</title>
<para>
Any register or state can be written in stage E (1) and up.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_SCHED_MIN_USE</title>
<para>
Any register or state can be read in stage E (1) and up.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_SCHED_SHARED_FUNCTION</title>
<para>
When a shared function is used multiple times in an operation/semantic,
each instance of the function is scheduled in a specific cycle, since
the hardware is shared. In some cases, no cycles can be found for a
shared function if the number of instances exceed the maximum latency
allowed for an instruction.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_SCHED_UNIQUE_STAGE</title>
<para>
All operands and states written in a schedule must have a unique
stage for use/def. For example, &quot;use a 1; use a 3;&quot; is an illegal
schedule since there is no unique use stage for a.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="WARN_DEFAULT_OFF">TIE_SCHED_USE_AFTER_DEF</title>
<para>
If an instruction reads and writes the same operand/state with a use stage
that is greater than the def stage, there may be a misconception that the
value read is the output of the same instruction. This is not the case.
All register (and state) reads happen when the instruction is issued 
in the register read (R) stage, and these values are piped down to the
appropriate use stage. In the case when the input operand/state is being
defined by another instruction in the pipeline, instead of waiting for
the instruction to update the register file and then read from it, the
data is forwarded from the previous instruction's output. But, there
is no data forwarding within the same instruction.
</para>
<para>
This warning is not seen by default. To see it, run TIE compiler with
the -warnall flag.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_SEAMLESS_NAME_LEN</title>
<para>
Mentor Graphics Seamless requires an upper limit of the length of 
certain identifiers. For configurations with Seamless option selected, 
TC reports an error if the requirement is violated.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_SEM_AMBIGUOUS_OPND_NAME</title>
<para>
The semantic shares operations and references.
An operation argument name is the same as an iclass operand name.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_SEMANTIC_CORE_SEMANTIC</title>
<para>
The semantic is already defined as a Xtensa core semantic.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_SEMANTIC_DUPLICATE_OPCODE</title>
<para>
The list of opcodes for a semantic must have unique opcode names.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON|ERR_ALLOW_IGNORE">TIE_SEM_FALSE_DEP</title>
<para>
When writing a combined semantic for multiple instructions with
different inputs and outputs, it is possible to introduce an error
which causes an incorrect dependency between the output of an instruction
to an input to the semantic that is not an input to the instruction. This
would cause incorrect functional behavior of the semantic.
</para>
<para>
If the instruction has a correct operation or reference description, running 
formal verification between the reference and the semantic would also point 
out such an error.
</para>
<para>
For example, in the following code, due to incorrect logic in the select
for wire &quot;b&quot;, the output of opcode &quot;I1&quot; will depend on art, which is 
invalid for the opcode.
</para>
<para>
iclass CLASS01 {I0, I1} {out arr, in ars } 
iclass CLASS2 {I2} {out arr, in ars, in art} 
semantic sem1 {I0, I1, I2 }
{
    wire [31:0] a = ars;
    wire [31:0] b = (~I0)?art:ars;
    assign arr = TIEadd(a,b,1'b1);
}
</para>
<para>
Warrning: (TIE_SEM_FALSE_DEP),
        Semantic &quot;sem1&quot;, output &quot;arr&quot; of instruction &quot;I1&quot;
        may depend on input &quot;art&quot; which is not in its iclass
</para>
<para>
Note that this is issued as a warning because the analysis of the
body of the instruction is done with algorithms which in some
rare case may generate a dependency which is not true. You
are thus strongly encouraged to review the semantic to verify that
there is no such dependence. If the dependence is real, it can result
in incorrect hardware and faulty silicon.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_SEM_MULTIPLE_DEF</title>
<para>
When combining instructions into a semantic, a common output of the
instructions must be written in the same stage for all of the instructions.
An output of a semantic cannot be written in different stages for 
different instructions.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_SEM_MULTIPLE_USE</title>
<para>
When combining instructions into a semantic, a common input of the
instructions must be read in the same stage for all of the instructions.
An input of a semantic cannot be read in different stages for 
different instructions.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON|ERR_ALLOW_IGNORE">TIE_SEM_NO_DEP</title>
<para>
When writing a combined semantic for multiple instructions with
different inputs and outputs, it is possible to introduce an error
which causes an input of an instruction to be ignored.
This would cause incorrect functional behavior of the semantic.
</para>
<para>
If the instruction has a correct reference, running formal verification
between the reference and the semantic would also point out this error.
</para>
<para>
For example, in the following code, due to incorrect logic in the select
for wire &quot;b&quot;, the input art of opcode &quot;I2&quot; will not be used to compute &quot;arr&quot;.
</para>
<para>
iclass CLASS01 {I0, I1} {out arr, in ars } 
iclass CLASS2 {I2} {out arr, in ars, in art} 
semantic sem1 {I0, I1, I2 }
{
    wire [31:0] a = ars;
    wire [31:0] b = (~I2)?art:ars;
    assign arr = TIEadd(a,b,1'b1);
}
</para>
<para>
Note that this is issued as a warning because the analysis of the
body of the instruction is done with algorithms which in some
rare case may generate a dependency which is not true.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_SEM_OPERATION_ARG_KIND</title>
<para>
When combining multiple operations into a semantic, the named arguments
of all operations must map to the same type of operand. For example,
in the following code, the operations &quot;OP1&quot; and &quot;OP2&quot; have different
kind of operands mapped to the name &quot;a&quot; and therefore cannot be combined
into a semantic.
</para>
<para>
operation OP1 { out AR c, in AR b, in simm8 a } {}
operation OP2 { out AR c, in AR a } {}
semantic alu { OP1, OP2 }
</para>
<para>
Error: (TIE_SEM_OPERATION_ARG_KIND),
        Semantic alu, argument &quot;a&quot; requires different kinds
        of operands for operations OP1 and OP2
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_SEM_OPERATION_ARG_TYPE</title>
<para>
When combining multiple operations into a semantic, the named arguments
of all operations must map to the same register file. For example,
in the following code, the operations &quot;OP1&quot; and &quot;OP2&quot; have different
register files mapped to the name &quot;a&quot; and therefore cannot be combined
into a semantic.
</para>
<para>
regfile XR 32 16 xr
operation OP1 { out AR c, in AR a } {}
operation OP2 { out AR c, in XR a } {}
semantic alu { OP1, OP2 }
</para>
<para>
Error: (TIE_SEM_OPERATION_ARG_TYPE),
        Semantic alu, argument &quot;a&quot; requires operands that
        access two different register files for operations OP1 and OP2
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_SEM_OPERATION_ARG_OPNDS</title>
<para>
When combining multiple operations into a semantic, the named arguments
of all operations must map to the same operands. For example,
in the following code, the operations &quot;OP1&quot; and &quot;OP2&quot; have different
operands mapped to the name &quot;a&quot; and therefore cannot be combined
into a semantic.
</para>
<para>
operation OP1 { out arr c, in ars a } {}
operation OP2 { out arr c, in art a } {}
semantic alu { OP1, OP2 }
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="WARN_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_SHIFT_AMOUNT</title>
<para>
Shift amount specified in expression will cause a larger than needed hardware.
This typically happens due to expressions involving integer constants which
are interpreted as 32 bit values. Example:
</para>
<para>
//incorrect
wire [31:0] val = ars &lt;&lt; 3;
//correct
wire [31:0] val = ars &lt;&lt; 2'd3;
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_SIGNEXTEND_ERR</title>
<para>
The usage of SignExtendFrom and SignExtendTo interface is wrong. 
The interfaces can only co-exist with MemDataIn32 interface. 
They can only be assigned to value 4 or less.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_SIMD_REDUCTION_ARG_DIR</title>
<para>
This error is generated for reduction property statements where one of
the protos, the &quot;init&quot;, &quot;vector&quot;, &quot;fini&quot; or &quot;scalar&quot; has an argument with
mismatched directions.
</para>
<para>
The init proto should have 2 arguments, an output with
the reduction type and an in with the scalar type.
</para>
<para>
The vector proto should have as many arguments as the scalar proto.
The first argument should be an output with the reduction type.  The
second should be an in with the reduction type.  The rest of the
arguments should all contain either the scalar type matching the one
in the scalar proto or a vector type with the appropriate vector
length corresponding to the one in the scalar proto.
</para>
<para>
The fini proto should have 2 arguments.  The first is an output with the
scalar type.  The second in an output with the reduction type.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_SIMD_REDUCTION_ARG_TYPE</title>
<para>
This error is generated for reduction property statements where one of
the protos, the &quot;init&quot;, &quot;vector&quot;, &quot;fini&quot; or &quot;scalar&quot; has an invalid argument
with mismatched directions.
</para>
<para>
The init proto should have 2 arguments, an output with
the reduction type and an in with the scalar type.
</para>
<para>
The vector proto should have as many arguments as the scalar proto.
The first argument should be an output with the reduction type.  The
second should be an in with the reduction type.  The rest of the
arguments should all contain either the scalar type matching the one
in the scalar proto or a vector type with the appropriate vector
length corresponding to the one in the scalar proto.
</para>
<para>
The fini proto should have 2 arguments.  The first is an output with the
scalar type.  The second in an output with the reduction type.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_SIMD_REDUCTION_ARG_VECTYPE</title>
<para>
This error is generated for the vector proto for a reduction property
statement where one of the arguments to the protos mismatches
the corresponding argument to the scalar proto.
</para>
<para>
For the vector proto, after the first 2 arguments, the rest
of the arguments must have the type of corresponding scalar proto
type or a vector type for that type with the appropriate vector length.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_SIMD_REDUCTION_CTYPE</title>
<para>
The ctype for a reduction operation must be a valid ctype.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_SIMD_REDUCTION_CTYPE_CASE</title>
<para>
The ctype for a reduction operation must be a valid ctype.  This message is
generated if there is a ctype that almost matches the one specified.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_SIMD_REDUCTION_NUM_ARGS</title>
<para>
This error is generated for reduction property statements where one of
the protos, the &quot;init&quot;, &quot;vector&quot;, &quot;fini&quot; or &quot;scalar&quot; has an invalid
number of protos.
</para>
<para>
The init proto should have 2 arguments, an output with
the reduction type and an in with the scalar type.
</para>
<para>
The vector proto should have as many arguments as the scalar proto.
The first argument should be an output with the reduction type.  The
second should be an in with the reduction type.  The rest of the
arguments should all contain either the scalar type matching the one
in the scalar proto or a vector type with the appropriate vector
length corresponding to the one in the scalar proto.
</para>
<para>
The fini proto should have 2 arguments.  The first is an output with the
scalar type.  The second in an output with the reduction type.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_SIMD_REDUCTION_OP</title>
<para>
This error is generated for reduction property statements where the scalar
proto is an intrinsic that does not allow user-reductions.
</para>
<para>
The intrinsics that are user-reducible are xt_add, xt_band, xt_bnand, 
xt_bnor, xt_bor, xt_bxor, xt_max, xt_min, xt_sub, xt_mpy, xt_madd, and 
xt_msub.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_SIMPLE_CONSTRUCT</title>
<para>
This error is only generated when you run the TIE compiler with the -chk_tiegen 
flag. It means that your TIE description does not fully specify all the 
information required to determine the opcode, operand and field encodings for 
all the TIE instructions.
</para>
<para>
The TIE compiler can automatically assign the encoding(s), but you are not 
guaranteed to always get the same encoding from one run to another. If you 
would like the TIE compiler to assign the encoding, you should run it 
without the -chk_tiegen flag. If you want to specify all the encodings
yourself, you must update the TIE description to address the specific
problem(s) highlighted with this error message.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_SLOT_ALL_SIZED</title>
<para>
The slots in a format should either be all explicitly assigned to bits
or all left to the TIE compiler to assign bits. A mix is not allowed.
Example:
</para>
<para>
length l64 64 { InstBuf[3:1] == 7 }
format vliw64 l64 { slot0, slot1, slot1 } { InstBuf[3:0] == 14 }
slot slot0 vliw64[20:5]   
slot slot1 vliw64[*]
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_SLOT_COMP_WRONG_INDEX_ORDER</title>
<para>
When assigning bits of a format to a slot, the order must be from:to, where
from is &gt; to.  Example:
</para>
<para>
length l64 64 { InstBuf[3:1] == 7 }
format vliw64 l64 { slot0, slot1, slot1 } { InstBuf[3:0] == 14 }
slot slot0 vliw64[20:5]   //legal
slot slot1 vliw64[32:63] //illegal
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_SLOT_COMP_WRONG_INDEX_RANGE</title>
<para>
When assigning bits of a format to a slot, the index must be within the range
of the instruction word.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_SLOT_DIFF_FORMAT</title>
<para>
A slot definition must have one format name only. For example, the following
is illegal
</para>
<para>
length  xlen64      64                  { InstBuf[3:0] == 15 }
</para>
<para>
format  xl64        xlen64   { slot0, slot1 }   { InstBuf[4] == 1'b0 }
format  ml64        xlen64   { slot0 }          { InstBuf[4] == 1'b1 }
</para>
<para>
slot    slot0       {xl64[29:10], ml64[9:5]}
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_SLOT_DIFF_SIZE</title>
<para>
A slot must have the same size when defined in multiple formats. For example,
the following is illegal
</para>
<para>
slot slot0 vliwa[21:0]
slot slot0 vliwb[21:4]
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_SLOT_MULTI_BIT</title>
<para>
The same bits of the instruction word can be used only once in a slot definition,
when the slot is defined as a concatenation of different bits of the format.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_SLOT_NO_NOP</title>
<para>
Every slot must have a NOP instruction in a multi-slot format so that the 
compiler can always generate a valid flix instruction. A nop is always
automatically added by the TIE compiler if the encoding space allows it.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_SLOT_NO_SLOT_OPCODE</title>
<para>
Every slot must have a &quot;slot_opcodes&quot; statement to indicate what opcodes
are allowed in that slot. A slot with no opcodes is not allowed. It must
have NOP at the least.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_SLOT_UNKNOWN_FORMAT</title>
<para>
The format name in the slot definition is not a known format.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_SLOT_UNUSABLE_BITS</title>
<para>
Slot contains some bits that cannot be used for encoding or operands.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_SLOT_OPCODE_FIELD_CONFLICT</title>
<para>
Slot and field names must be unique in a case insensitive way to avoid
naming conflicts in TIE compiler generated code.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_SLOT_OPCODES_SLOT_UNDEFINED</title>
<para>
The slot name in the slot_opcodes definition is not a known slot.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_SREG_NAME_CONFLICT</title>
<para>
The user register specified will have a name conflict with an existing user register.
For example, a user register cannot be named &quot;PS&quot; because there is a special
register &quot;PS&quot; in the Xtensa core.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_SREG_OPCODE_USED</title>
<para>
The user register specified will generate opcodes that will
have a name conflict with an existing user register.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_STATE_ALREADY_MAPPED</title>
<para>
The same state cannot be mapped to multiple user registers, if a user register
is manually written for a state, it cannot have the add_read_write option as well.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_STATE_CORE_STATE</title>
<para>
A Xtensa core state with the same name is defined. State names must be unique
in a case-insensitive way.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_STATE_EXPORT_INIT</title>
<para>
All export states must have a initial value. This is the value of the state
when Xtensa comes out of reset. If no initial value is assigned, the state
value is unknown until it is written in the program.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="WARN_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_STATE_INIT_WIDTH</title>
<para>
The width of state initialization value need to be within the state width. 
In the case that the state width is exceeded, the upper bits are ignored.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_STATE_MAX_WIDTH</title>
<para>
Maximum width of a state is 1024 bits.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_STATE_MULTIPLE_MAP</title>
<para>
The same bits of a state cannot be mapped to multiple user registers.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_STATE_NO_DEF</title>
<para>
There are no writes to the state from any instruction. Note that
&quot;add_read_write&quot; automatically generates &quot;RUR/WUR&quot; instructions
that read and write the state.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON|WARN_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_STATE_NO_UREG_MAP</title>
<para>
A state has to be fully mapped to user-registers if it belongs to 
a coprocessor, so that the state can be saved and restored upon
coprocessor exception and context switch.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_STATE_NO_USE</title>
<para>
There are no reads from the state from any instruction. Note that
&quot;add_read_write&quot; automatically generates &quot;RUR/WUR&quot; instructions
that read and write the state.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_STATE_SHARED_OR</title>
<para>
The following limitations are imposed on states with &quot;shared_or&quot; attributes:
1. The states cannot be killed. If state value is conditionally assigned, 
   set the state direction as inout and assign the input value instead. 
2. The states cannot appear in the instructions containing memory, import wire,
   queue, or lookup interfaces.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_STATE_USE_DEF</title>
<para>
The earliest use stage of a state must be less than on equal to the
maximum def stage of the state, to ensure correct implementation.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_SUBFIELD_NOT_DEFINED</title>
<para>
If a field is defined as a concatenation of other subfields, all the
subfields must be defined.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_SUBSCRIPT</title>
<para>
Illegal subscript. Legal subscript syntax is name[from:to] where :
</para>
<list>
<item><itemtext>both from and to are within the bounds of the size of the variable,
i.e. &gt;=0 and &lt;= size - 1.</itemtext>
</item>
<item><itemtext>from &gt;= to</itemtext>
</item>
</list>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_TABLE_CORE_TABLE</title>
<para>
The table name is already defined in the Xtensa core.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_TABLE_FIELD_CONFLICT</title>
<para>
The table name conflicts with a field name. Table names must be unique.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_TABLE_ILLEGAL_WIDTH</title>
<para>
The width of a table entry must be &gt; 0 and &lt;= 32 bits.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_TABLE_ILLEGAL_ENTRY</title>
<para>
The entry in the table uses more than 32 bits.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_TABLE_NUM_ELEMENTS</title>
<para>
The number of elements in the table is larger than the size of the table.
Note that if the table has less elements than the size, it is zero padded.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_TABLE_USE</title>
<para>
A table can be indexed with a single index only. TABLE[from:to] is ambiguous.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="WARN_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_TABLE_VALUE</title>
<para>
The entry value in the table does not fit in the width of the table.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON|WARN_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_TIEGEN</title>
<para>
TIE compiler failed to generate the correct encoding for operations
and flix formats. This is usually accompanied by a detailed message
about the specific error cause.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_PORT_PROTECT</title>
<para>
If the Xtensa configuration has an MMU, all tieports must have some
protection implemented. This is done by putting every tieport in a
coprocessor such that the the coprocessors can be disabled for 
certain tasks to achieve some protection.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_TPP_EXEC_FAIL</title>
<para>
Could not run the TIE perl preprocessor.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="WARN_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_UNDERUTILIZED_RANGE</title>
<para>
The immediate range specified is using bits that are not all utilized.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_UNIMPLEMENTABLE_RANGE</title>
<para>
The immediate range specified cannot be efficiently implemented.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_UREG_NAME</title>
<para>
User registers should be defined with names only. Numbers are not needed.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_UREG_NAME_ALLOC</title>
<para>
The user register name specified will generate opcodes that conflict with
an existing operation or another user register.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_UREG_NAME_ALREADY_USED</title>
<para>
The user register name specified is already used.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_UREG_NAME_CONFLICT</title>
<para>
The user register name specified will conflict with another name.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_UREG_NAME_ILLEGAL</title>
<para>
User register names of the form &quot;UR[number]&quot; should not be used.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_UREG_NO_MAP</title>
<para>
No state mapped to the user register.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_UREG_NO_STATE</title>
<para>
The state name in the user register definition does not exist.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="WARN_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_UREG_NUMBER</title>
<para>
User TIE should use user register numbers from 0-223. Note that user registers
should be written with name only so that TIE compiler can automatically assign
an appropriate number.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_UREG_NUMBER_ALLOC</title>
<para>
TIE compiler could not allocate a user register number because all valid numbers
are used.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_UREG_NUM_ALREADY_USED</title>
<para>
The user register number specified is already used. Note that user registers
should be written with name only so that TIE compiler can automatically assign
an appropriate number.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_UREG_OPCODE_USED</title>
<para>
The RUR/WUR opcode is already defined manually, so TIE compiler cannot generate
these automatically.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_UREG_SIZE</title>
<para>
A user register can map only 32 bits of a state. Wider states should be mapped
to multiple user registers. Note that TIE compiler automatically generates
user registers for all bits of a state with the &quot;add_read_write&quot; option.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_UREG_STATE_BITS</title>
<para>
User register maps state bits outside the valid range, must be &gt;=0 and &lt;= state width - 1.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_UREG_STATE_NAME_CONFLICT</title>
<para>
A user register cannot have the same name as a state unless it has a one to one mapping
from a state. A user register that maps only a few bits of a state, or maps multiple states
must be named differently. This is to avoid naming confusion in the debugger.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_WIRE_CYCLIC_DEP</title>
<para>
The wire in the semantic depends on itself. For example,
</para>
<verbatim><![CDATA[
wire [31:0] xx;
wire [31:0] yy;
assign xx = art + yy;
assign yy = ars + xx;
]]></verbatim>
<para>
Error: (TIE_WIRE_CYCLIC_DEP),
        The declared wires in the assignment block have cyclic
        dependency involving xx ,yy
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_WIRE_DECL</title>
<para>
Illegal wire declaration. Wires should be declared as [from:to] where both
&quot;from&quot; and &quot;to&quot; are &gt;=0 and from is greater than to.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_XCC_MAX_NUM</title>
<para>
XCC requires that the total number of states, register files, and ports
is less than 1024. The total number of ports includes
ports generated from TIE queues (3 ports per queue), import
wires (1 port), export states (1 port) and TIE lookup (2 ports per
lookup without Rdy, and 3 with Rdy).
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title default="ERR_DEFAULT_ON">TIE_XTENSA_CONFIG</title>
<para>
This feature is not supported by the base Xtensa core used.
</para>
</sect2>
</sect1>
</pod>
